<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Stefano YT RSS]]></title>
    <link>https://st-costa.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://st-costa.github.io/YT_highlight_feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Feed di highlights dei video YouTube]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:16:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] The Dark Subcultures of Online Politics - Joshua Citarella]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qNCHDE1vgS8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 23:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qNCHDE1vgS8">The Dark Subcultures of Online Politics - Joshua Citarella</a></h1>
<h2>The Meme-Driven Evolution of Political Subcultures  </h2>
The guest explains how online meme culture among teenagers has predicted and shaped wider political trends, moving from niche internet subcultures to mainstream influence. The transformation of fringe ideas into mass movements reflects the scaling power of digital media.
<p>&gt; &quot;We now see those same narratives and in some cases literally the same memes posted to audiences in the hundreds of thousands or millions. So the scale on these things, we call it early detection. How do you find something that is going to get big in the future? It&apos;s like political trend casting.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Rise of Right-Wing Populism and Shifting Party Coalitions  </h2>
There’s been a dramatic and unexpected global shift toward right-wing populism, even among groups that historically aligned with labor interests—surprising both political analysts and the left.
<p>&gt; &quot;The thing that has come out of it to the great surprise of people on the left is not like a renewed trade unionism... but it is this new international nationalism. We don&apos;t yet know what to call it but generally the rise of right-wing populism as a push back to austerity anti-immigration politics this kind of stuff.&quot;</p>
<h2>Gen Z’s Unique Political Context: Information Overload and Lack of Consensus  </h2>
Unlike past generations, Gen Z grew up with boundless information access and no clear political consensus, fostering experimentation with countless ideologies and accelerating radicalization pipelines.
<p>&gt; &quot;Growing up in Gen Z, you don&apos;t have that 1989 liberal democracy consensus... Instead, you are born into a world that has no political answers for you while you&apos;re given the complete archive of the internet to tr trudge through every possible meme and political text that&apos;s ever written...&quot;</p>
<h2>Irony, [__]posting, and the Problem of Earnest Belief  </h2>
Much of online radicalization and meme culture blurs the line between irony and sincerity, with users sometimes adopting extreme views they originally forwarded only as jokes, a process dubbed "irony poisoning.”
<p>&gt; &quot;Irony poisoning is when you float something that is a joke and then you say this is not what I really believe but I&apos;m posting it to like piss off the libs or something like that and then a few years later you kind of like work your way up to it and you&apos;re like actually yeah this is what I believe.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Pipeline Metaphor: Fluid Political Identities and Media Narratives  </h2>
The concept of radicalization as a “pipeline” is both useful and misleading, as media often exaggerates its implications, while in reality, people’s political identities and coalitions are constantly shifting.
<p>&gt; &quot;The great irony of like the pipeline metaphor to me was that belief systems are in motion. I think actually all belief systems are in motion. ...when they talk about very popular podcasts being a pipeline to extremist politics... I think that that is a gross gross mischaracterization.&quot;</p>
<h2>Online Communities as Real-World Political Actors  </h2>
Fringe digital groups can emerge as active political forces, influencing everything from street activism to electoral campaigns—sometimes outpacing traditional parties in grassroots mobilization.
<p>&gt; &quot;During the Georgia Senate runoff, he [Destiny] mobilized his Twitch followers and had more people canvasing and knocking doors than the Capital D Democratic Party... the call to action from a media entity is larger than a proper political party.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Left’s Struggle with Masculinity and Losing Young Men  </h2>
The guest examines how contemporary left-wing movements, especially in academic and activist spaces, have alienated young men, leading them towards other political alternatives—even when some seek to participate constructively.
<p>&gt; &quot;I would hear just... endless kind of casual misandry and these people&apos;s political needs are not important and it&apos;s their turn to take a back seat. It&apos;s like this is really going to bubble over. This is this is not good. ...they would just be met with like this kind of vicious activist rhetoric that was meant to basically scare them off...&quot;</p>
<h2>Horseshoe Theory and the Unpredictable Alliances of Modern Politics  </h2>
Anti-establishment sentiments now drive people to unexpected combinations of right and left views, with new voting patterns emerging that blur traditional ideological boundaries.
<p>&gt; &quot;So there is a noninssignificant portion of the population that voted for Trump in 2024 and Mumani in 2025... those people exist. So they&apos;re they&apos;re open they&apos;re open to a lot of ideas.&quot;</p>
<h2>Performance Activism, Effectiveness, and Generational Disconnect  </h2>
Public stunts by climate activists and others often fail to persuade the broader public, as effective movement-building requires appealing to practical interests and building broad, inclusive coalitions.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you join some political organization, and all they can tell you is like, &apos;Well, no airplanes, no hamburgers, we&apos;re going to take stuff away from people.&apos; ...That doesn&apos;t work anymore. And so they voluntarily just exit those types of movements.&quot;</p>
<h2>Personal Hardship, Resilience, and Shaping Worldview  </h2>
The host and guest connect their own health challenges to greater empathy and understanding of societal vulnerability, with hardship sometimes fostering deeper resilience and more nuanced politics.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s so front and center of your experience that if you are dealing with something, especially something that affects your energy or your cognition or your mood, like it&apos;s the window through which you experience the world. It&apos;s like looking at the world through a dirty window.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] How to Build Systems (So Your Business Runs Without You)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEK5CZy17Ng</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:42:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEK5CZy17Ng">How to Build Systems (So Your Business Runs Without You)</a></h1>
<h2>Escaping the Bottleneck: Make Yourself Less Essential</h2>
<p>The more your business depends on you, the harder it becomes to grow or exit. To build a valuable, scalable company, deliberately remove yourself from daily operations and shift key responsibilities to others, aiming to work on the business rather than in it.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;The more valuable you are, the less valuable the company is.&quot;</p>
<h2>From Doer to Owner: Move to the Owner’s Box</h2>
<p>Entrepreneurs must choose between being the all-star player or truly owning their business. Decide to let go of control, transition to leadership roles, and cultivate a team and systems that operate independently, freeing you for big-picture strategy and rest.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Do you want to be down on the court hitting the last minute...jump shot, or do you want to be up in the owner’s box?&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Default Constraints to Force Real Change</h2>
<p>Establish hard boundaries for your time—like set working hours—to force prioritization and empower your team. Default constraints quickly reveal what’s essential and help break old habits, creating space to actually step out of the weeds.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I&apos;m going to leave at 5:30 every day...and what do you know? Magically I got my work done in that block of time because I did.&quot;</p>
<h2>Map Your Business Processes for Clarity and Delegation</h2>
<p>Visually map every core process (e.g., how you get customers, serve them, and create products) with tools like whiteboards and sticky notes. This makes workflow bottlenecks obvious and enables delegation of responsibilities.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Every business does three things. You make stuff, you sell stuff, and you fulfill stuff...create a visual map of how that happens.&quot;</p>
<h2>Identify and Focus on the Biggest Constraint</h2>
<p>Stop adding new ideas and instead consistently identify the single largest constraint blocking growth—whether it’s demand (more leads) or supply (capacity to handle leads)—and focus resources on solving only that next hurdle.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What is my right next thing? What is the thing that I&apos;m going to do next? Every problem in business is going to come down to one of two things. Is it a supply constraint or a demand constraint?&quot;</p>
<h2>Hire Functional Leaders, Not Helpers or Clones</h2>
<p>Don’t just hire assistants or try to clone yourself. To scale, deliberately seek skilled functional leaders—heads of sales, marketing, product—who can own entire business areas without your micromanagement.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What you need to typically do is realize that that constraint is solved by a functional leader...hiring a functional leader and building a team of those...&quot;</p>
<h2>Assign Clear Accountability and Metrics for Each Step</h2>
<p>For every step in your mapped processes, assign direct ownership and transparent success metrics. This enables team members to be true drivers (not just helpers) and clarifies both individual and team accountability.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Every single sticky note, every single box is going to have corresponding what we would call critical accountability bullets...this is how we create our scorecards.&quot;</p>
<h2>Only Systemize What Matters Most</h2>
<p>Systematize only the crucial parts of your operation, not everything. Focus documentation, measurement, and optimization on your most important “value engines.” Ignore or eliminate orphaned activities that don’t meaningfully drive results.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;One of the biggest mistakes that companies make when they&apos;re trying to systemize is they try to document everything. Don&apos;t do that. Just document the ones that are really, really, really important.&quot;</p>
<h2>Build a Company Top Talent Wants to Join</h2>
<p>If you want to attract great talent, develop systems and a culture where they can succeed without heroic individual efforts. Systems attract rockstars because they see they can make an impact—and these systems allow you to succeed even without “A-players.&quot;</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;My goal is to build a company that doesn&apos;t require them because I know that&apos;s the kind of company that rockstars and a players want to come and work for.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[HBR] Future of Business: Mars CEO on How Business Can Be a Force for Good]]></title>
      <link>https://hbr.org/podcast/2025/12/future-of-business-mars-ceo-on-how-business-can-be-a-force-for-good</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:47:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[HBR] <a href="https://hbr.org/podcast/2025/12/future-of-business-mars-ceo-on-how-business-can-be-a-force-for-good">Future of Business: Mars CEO on How Business Can Be a Force for Good</a></h1>
<h2>Long-Term Vision Enables Sustainable Growth  </h2>
Building a strategy for sustainability requires a balance between delivering short-term performance and long-term value, made possible by a long-term ownership mindset. Prioritize decisions that set up your company for success across decades, not just quarters.
<p>&gt; &quot;We’d like to think we think in generations and not just in quarters. And because of our ownership, we carry the name of our owners on the door, we have an obligation to make sure that we behave well in society.&quot;</p>
<h2>Tie Incentives to Non-Financial Goals  </h2>
Integrate sustainability metrics into compensation to drive accountability at all management levels. By making social and environmental impact part of leaders' measurable objectives, you embed purpose into daily business.
<p>&gt; &quot;40% of my compensation is on non-financial metrics... I would say to a public listed CEO, &apos;How do you feel about having 40% of your compensation on greenhouse gases?&apos;&quot;</p>
<h2>Engage Supply Chain Partners for Real Impact  </h2>
Most environmental impact may occur outside your company in the supply chain. Build deep relationships with suppliers and invest in tools (like satellite imaging) and systems to ensure responsible sourcing and drive change with farmers and producers.
<p>&gt; &quot;About 85% of our environmental footprint sits outside the company, so what is called Scope 3... and that is working with predominantly farmers across the world.&quot;</p>
<h2>Make Sustainability a Core Business Process  </h2>
Incorporate sustainability reviews and investment decisions directly into regular business planning. Treat environmental impact assessments and investments as integral as financial planning.
<p>&gt; &quot;We have tried to integrate sustainability in the way we do business... when we review the plan... we are reviewing the investment levels in sustainability in our food business, our pet food business, our snacking business, and in our veterinary business.&quot;</p>
<h2>Invest in Innovation that Balances Purpose and Profit  </h2>
Embrace the challenge of aligning purpose with profit by reframing sustainability as an opportunity for innovation and growth, rather than a trade-off.
<p>&gt; &quot;Purpose and profit are not enemies, that it is our task that we have to do both... a lot of that has come from products where we have done work on sustainability.&quot;</p>
<h2>Align Product Changes to Tangible Customer Benefits  </h2>
When communicating sustainability efforts, focus on clear, product-specific changes that directly improve environmental outcomes. Consumers respond best to transparent, concrete claims.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you advertise a positive environmental impact of a product close to the product, i.e. you explain the exact thing you have changed on a product, then that brand will benefit... recyclable packaging, consumers absolutely understand.&quot;</p>
<h2>Building Resilient Supply Chains  </h2>
Localize production where possible and diversify sources to weather geopolitical and climate-related disruptions. Resilience is crucial for stability and continuing to serve customers in an unpredictable world.
<p>&gt; &quot;The most important thing is resiliency, to build up a supply chain that is resilient enough to take some of these hits that are coming with political issues across the globe.&quot;</p>
<h2>Foster Empathy and Self-Awareness in Leadership  </h2>
Cultivate empathetic, self-aware leaders who listen and build a respectful, inclusive workplace. Recognize that societal issues increasingly enter the business sphere, and leaders must navigate them with openness and care.
<p>&gt; &quot;The most important thing as leader is to have empathy and listen... Self-awareness is more important today than what it was in the past because the softer values of leadership are much more in focus.&quot;</p>
<h2>Capital Allocation Based on Clear, Goal-Linked Methodology  </h2>
Allocate capital towards both financial and sustainability goals, recognizing that not every investment will have the same financial ROI, but some are essential for social responsibility and long-term value.
<p>&gt; &quot;We have an allocated number in sustainability that is linked to our goal. So we want to reduce by X percent at that date and we work what are the investments required to achieve that goal... not all of our investments have the same requirements.&quot;</p>
<h2>Over-Invest in Continuous Personal Learning  </h2>
Stay innovative by fostering personal curiosity and lifelong learning, both for yourself and your teams. Encouraging ongoing development is essential for remaining adaptive and inventive in a changing world.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you go back and study what really constitutes the most important elements of leadership, the most important is personal learning. It has the biggest correlation. And the way you learn, you need high curiosity.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] Improve Energy & Longevity by Optimizing Mitochondria | Dr. Martin Picard]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMkQUlBtFlk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:01:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMkQUlBtFlk">Improve Energy &amp; Longevity by Optimizing Mitochondria | Dr. Martin Picard</a></h1>
<h2>Aging and Hair Graying Are Not Fixed—You Can Reverse It by Managing Stress</h2>
<p>Science now shows that graying hair is not always a permanent, irreversible sign of aging. Stress can accelerate graying, and reducing stress can actually reverse it, at least temporarily. If you notice your hair going gray, take it as a sign to examine stress in your life and find manageable ways to reduce or cope with it—like improving sleep, meditating, or creating a restorative routine.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What we discovered is that hair graying, at least temporarily, is reversible. This was surprising because it goes against this notion that aging is a linear... process that just happens over time no matter what you do.&quot;</p>
<h2>Energy Is About Flow, Not Just Intake—Focus on Transformation, Not Calories</h2>
<p>Energy in the body isn’t just about eating more; it’s about how well your mitochondria transform and distribute that energy. Overeating or eating poorly doesn’t give you more energy—it can actually make you more sluggish. Instead, focus on behaviors that boost your mitochondria’s ability to transform energy, such as regular exercise, quality sleep, and stress reduction.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Just consuming more energy didn&apos;t give you more energy... the issue is not lack of energy going into the system. It&apos;s that the transformation of energy that occurs in mitochondria somehow is not happening correctly.&quot;</p>
<h2>Tailor Your Habits to Enhance Mitochondrial Health (And Thus, Your Vitality)</h2>
<p>To boost your energy and aging trajectory, go beyond simply exercising and eating well. Quality sleep, meditation, and aligning activities with your sense of purpose and enjoyment all support healthier, more efficient mitochondria. Regular movement, being “out of breath” each day, and occasional hunger (like skipping breakfast sometimes) can also optimize mitochondrial function.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There are critical things that you can do in terms of how you eat, your mindset, and exercise that can offset those changes. His lab also famously showed that graying of hair is indeed related to stress and is also fortunately reversible.&quot;</p>
<h2>Too Much or Too Little Resistance Is Harmful—Strike a Balance in Life and Training</h2>
<p>Growth, learning, and physical improvement require the right amount of resistance or challenge. When resistance is too high, it’s overwhelming and can break you; too little, and the body and mind atrophy. In both exercise and life, consciously select activities and problems that push you enough to foster adaptation, but not so much that you’re crushed.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;The art of education is finding the right amount of resistance to expose a child to. If the problem is too hard... you crush them. If you don&apos;t apply any resistance there&apos;s no rules then the energy is like this and then they&apos;ll never learn. There needs to be just the sweet spot.&quot;</p>
<h2>Purpose and Positive Social Connections Directly Improve Brain Energy</h2>
<p>Doing things that inspire you and building real connections with others tangibly improve mitochondrial function in your brain. Focus on meaning and relationships as intentionally as you do diet and exercise, since psychological fulfillment helps prevent depression and bolsters mental and physical resilience.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;People who felt more purpose in life and who felt more connected to others... seemed like was sufficient to increase the energy transformation capacity of the mitochondria in their brain.&quot;</p>
<h2>Sleep and Meditation Conserve and Restore Energy—Prioritize Them Actively</h2>
<p>You can’t “out-eat” or “out-supplement” poor sleep. Sleep and deep relaxation free up energy for repair, healing, and growth. Incorporate restful pre-sleep routines, naps, or even daily meditation, as these deliberately reduce the energy “cost” of stress and allow your mitochondria to recharge, leading to better overall performance and mental clarity.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Meditating it seems and in some trained people can bring energy expenditure down by 40%. This is more than sleep.&quot;</p>
<h2>Being Mindful of Inflammation Saves Energy for What Matters</h2>
<p>Inflammation, whether from illness, overeating, or chronic stress, drains your energy and reduces what’s available for living, thinking, moving, and feeling good. Prioritize anti-inflammatory habits like regular activity, occasional fasting, and especially managing stress—to keep inflammation and its energetic “tax” low.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Inflammation is an energetic signal. If there are cytoines in your blood, somewhere in your body... the major cytoines that we think about... it&apos;s recruiting the fat. It recruits the liver. And it sends signal to the brain... you need to recover.&quot;</p>
<h2>There Is No One-Size-Fits-All Diet—Experiment to Find Your Best Pattern</h2>
<p>Scientific studies on diets often average out huge individual differences. Tune into your body’s response—try different eating patterns, such as intermittent fasting or low-carb, and stick with what&apos;s energizing and sustainable for you. Safe self-experimentation can reveal what genuinely boosts your vitality and mitochondrial health.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s no one diet that is a best diet for everyone. I&apos;ve seen people thrive on very different diets... Safe self-experimentation is the only solution.&quot;</p>
<h2>Avoid Excessive Use of Stimulants and Energy “Borrowing” Substances</h2>
<p>Stimulants like amphetamines, cocaine, or even excessive caffeine can temporarily mask fatigue, but they “borrow” energy from the future and can cause long-term damage to your energy system. Use them sparingly, if at all, and be mindful of how you truly feel—opt for natural energy-building strategies first.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;You&apos;re borrowing energy from the future is what you&apos;re doing. And it&apos;s not just the crash that happens later. It&apos;s the long-term effects of this.&quot;</p>
<h2>Build Daily Energy with Small, Consistent Habits</h2>
<p>Simple tweaks such as skipping breakfast occasionally (“being hungry once in a while”), ensuring at least some daily physical activity that elevates your breath and pulse, and practicing mindfulness or meditation can all meaningfully improve how your body makes, transforms, and allocates energy—improving both healthspan and lifespan.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Trying to be hungry once in a while is probably a good thing. And then being out of breath... that&apos;s probably good for you. I need to say something about meditation. I think somehow meditation does something to our energy that is valuable.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] Why Comedies Suck Now - Judd Apatow (4K)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9p0NbOWWsgI</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:01:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9p0NbOWWsgI">Why Comedies Suck Now - Judd Apatow (4K)</a></h1>
<h2>Channeling Pain and Discomfort into Creativity</h2>
<p>Harness personal challenges and discomfort as fuel for creative or professional pursuits. Use difficult experiences to develop new perspectives and heightened observation skills—the sensitivity gained from hardship often becomes a catalyst for success and originality across fields like comedy, music, and business.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;discomfort and pain seems to be a real creative catalyst...it just makes you more sensitive and I think you just pay attention in a different way to the world and you don&apos;t feel safe.&quot;</p>
<h2>Practicing in Public and Embracing Creative Failure</h2>
<p>Accept that developing performance or public skills often requires learning in front of others and embracing failure as a necessary step. Treat “bombing” or public mistakes as valuable R&amp;D, not something to hide from, and use the information to improve as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;the only profession that you have to learn how to do it in front of people...I&apos;m bombing but I&apos;m in it. This is it. We&apos;re doing it. So I got kind of excited even after a bomb that I was entering the business.&quot;</p>
<h2>Separating Creation from Critique to Boost Output</h2>
<p>When working on something creative, separate the “flow” or generation phase from the evaluation or critique phase. Write, perform, or brainstorm freely first, then return in a different mindset to judge what’s valuable. This method builds momentum and diminishes destructive overthinking.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I try to separate the the flow moment from the judgment moment and I think that people slow down because they&apos;re trying to do it at the same time.&quot;</p>
<h2>Find Value in Mentorship and Trusted Feedback</h2>
<p>Actively seek mentors who genuinely understand your work and can provide honest, constructive advice. Surround yourself with collaborators who aren’t afraid to challenge or correct you, and recognize that their perspective can fuel growth and confidence.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;he let me write the Grammys for him and then he hired me...just that he liked it put so much gas in my tank...him being gone I think has really hurt me because it really was one of the things I leaned on.&quot;</p>
<h2>Collaboration and “Being a Good Hang” Matter</h2>
<p>Professional success in creative fields is not just about talent—it’s about being enjoyable and reliable to work with. Foster strong collaborative environments and avoid being a “room killer,” as your attitude can impact both opportunities and long-term relationships.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;if you&apos;re not cool and they&apos;re on the bubble about whether or not to do it, they&apos;re always not going to do it if they don&apos;t want to have that relationship... part of it is like do people want you around.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Public Nature of Progress: Status and Comparison</h2>
<p>Regular comparison to peers and public performance can drive insecurities but also motivate improvement. Recognize that careers often require enduring periods where others seem to succeed faster, but focusing on personal growth and unique paths can lead to long-term fulfillment.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I would get depressed...trying to figure out, you know, what am I going to do here? Because I was young...I wasn&apos;t groundbreaking...But it took a long time for me to find myself almost till you know freaks and geeks where I realized oh the more personal I am the better it is...&quot;</p>
<h2>The Cycle and Value of Originality in Comedy (and Other Creative Work)</h2>
<p>Understand that trends in creative industries are cyclical, and true innovation often comes from outsiders with fewer resources who take risks. Don’t wait for gatekeepers&apos; approval—sometimes pioneering work means starting small, permissionlessly, and proving value over time.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;we have the technology we just need some lunatics to make something groundbreaking now cheap because that&apos;s what changes the genre is that someone just did...&quot;</p>
<h2>Navigating Feedback: Taking Criticism and Saying “No”</h2>
<p>Learn to create a culture where honest, sometimes uncomfortable feedback is welcomed. Value those who can critique you constructively—even in high-stakes scenarios, this openness improves the quality of your work. Be prepared to defend your vision when it matters most, but remain open to changing it when given good reason.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;you invite all your friends and friends of friends who are writers and then you have to tell them, &apos;Okay, hit me with the truth.&apos; There&apos;s nothing you can say that will offend me...create a space where people will say what they feel. And it&apos;s always helpful.&quot;</p>
<h2>Overdelivering and Working for Free Early in Careers</h2>
<p>At the start of your career, don’t be afraid to offer your work for free or go beyond expectations to break in and build relationships. Consistently overdeliver so you become indispensable, opening doors to paid opportunities and skill development.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I just wanted to overd deliver it to a ridiculous extreme. So if Shan wanted a few jokes for the Grammys, I&apos;d write him a hundred...no one is going to outwork him. And maybe when I wasn&apos;t as good, but it mattered because I cared so much.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] The 2025 Milly Awards]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xGL-H9vQI-8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-6</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xGL-H9vQI-8">The 2025 Milly Awards</a></h1>
<h2>Redefining Investment: Prioritize Life Upgrades, Not Just Finance</h2>
Don’t limit “investment” to just stocks and bonds—consider moves that make your life happier and richer. Prioritizing emotional and personal returns, like proximity to loved ones or simplifying your lifestyle, can have a profound impact on daily wellbeing. Consider downsizing, moving closer to friends or family, or offloading possessions to increase happiness.
<p>&gt; “Owning less stuff, moving to the city, being near your family, working in person in an office. That&apos;s actually a pretty big change overall. Huge change. It&apos;s definitely made me a lot happier.”</p>
<h2>Embrace Specific and Public Financial Bets with Long-Term Intentions</h2>
Making lump-sum investments based on conviction, and holding for the long term—and even sharing your decisions publicly—can clarify your thinking and boost returns. Commit to assets you believe in for at least a decade, rather than chasing trends.
<p>&gt; “...what companies or assets do I want to own for like a 10 year period? 10 years is my sort of default hold period. And that&apos;s what I&apos;ve been doing since then.”</p>
<h2>Seek Out High Agency Decisions and Take Action on Conviction</h2>
Recognize when unique opportunities align with your expertise or intuition, and act quickly. Many missed opportunities come from hesitation or not responding to outreach for partnerships or investments, even when you have an advantage.
<p>&gt; “I passed on three different, $10 billion startup investments that were right in my wheelhouse...all I needed to do was answer.”</p>
<h2>Pursue a “Misogi”: A Big, Year-Defining Personal Challenge</h2>
Designate one demanding goal or challenge—physical, creative, or emotional—each year to create lasting memories and personal growth. Pick a challenge that feels surreal or intimidating, put it on the calendar, and document your progress.
<p>&gt; “One of his core concept is this concept of a Misogi…a hard year defining thing. So you&apos;ll always remember, oh, that was the year I hiked...that was the year I did my first Ironman...you&apos;ll always remember.”</p>
<h2>Use Money Deliberately to Build Community and Happiness</h2>
Instead of only using money to upgrade your lifestyle, use it to enhance community and social connection—such as by living close to friends or creating intentional shared spaces. This leads to greater well-being than simply buying more or bigger things.
<p>&gt; “The people you have around you, your close-knit community is the number one thing that will improve your happiness. So we did that...built their own little micro community.”</p>
<h2>Frame-Breaking Hospitality and the Power of Radical Excellence</h2>
Strive for not just good, but “unreasonable” excellence in any pursuit—whether it’s business or personal—by over-delivering and weaving delight into small details. High intentionality and caring execution can set you apart dramatically.
<p>&gt; “We are going to go above and beyond and we are going to be excellent...pursuing excellence for the sake of just trying to be great at a couple things.”</p>
<h2>Delete Social Apps to Reclaim Time for Deep Work and Reading</h2>
If distraction and shallow content are draining your focus, delete social media apps or set up strict boundaries. Free up hours for rich, high-quality inputs, like reading books, and notice the improvement in clarity and depth of thought.
<p>&gt; “I took my phone and I just deleted X, deleted Twitter, deleted YouTube, deleted Reddit...I&apos;m just going to not consume any social this year.”</p>
<h2>Reset Your Morning Routine for Maximum Impact</h2>
Start your day with early, consistent workouts to set a productive tone and improve focus. Finish your workout by 7 a.m., and go to bed at 10 p.m. to sustain the habit.
<p>&gt; “My workout is finished at 7 a.m. I&apos;m done by 7 a.m...the secret is you have to go to bed at 10.”</p>
<h2>Running: Accessible High-Return Habit for Body and Mind</h2>
Running is a habit nearly anyone can adopt, with measurable progress and emotional benefits. Start at a pace that feels comfortable—even if it’s slow—and build up gradually. Stick with it to see life-changing improvements in health and mindset.
<p>&gt; “I think anyone can get to the point where they&apos;re running marathons, running three miles a day. That&apos;s how I started....You will get to a point where your body, you know, becomes more efficient. And over time, you&apos;re going to be running 10 minute miles at that walking feeling pace and you&apos;re going to love running.”</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] How to Set & Achieve Goals | Huberman Lab Essentials]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYuw-8pwnp8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-7</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:01:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYuw-8pwnp8">How to Set &amp; Achieve Goals | Huberman Lab Essentials</a></h1>
<h2>Set Moderately Challenging, Concrete Goals  </h2>
The most effective goals are those that are challenging yet achievable; they should feel slightly out of reach, but not impossible or too easy. To maintain motivation and activate your physiological systems, aim for goals that stretch your current abilities.
<p>&gt; &quot;So it turns out that when goals were moderate, when they were just outside of one&apos;s immediate abilities or that one felt that yeah, that would take a lot of effort but it&apos;s within range or maybe in range like maybe I can do it, maybe I can&apos;t, then there was a near doubling of the likelihood that they would engage in the ongoing pursuit of that particular goal.&quot;</p>
<h2>Focus Visual Attention on a Distant Point to Boost Motivation  </h2>
Before starting a task or whenever you need to take action toward a goal, pick a specific point outside your immediate reach (on a wall, or in the distance) and hold your gaze there for 30–60 seconds. This primes your body and brain for action by recruiting your attention, increasing alertness, and raising blood pressure.
<p>&gt; &quot;You&apos;re going to focus your visual attention on one point beyond your perpersonal space...and with some effort, you&apos;re going to hold your visual attention for 30 to 60 seconds...Again, it places your brain and body into a state of readiness. And then the idea is to move into the particular actions that bring you closer to your goal.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Foreshadowing Failure to Sustain Effort  </h2>
Instead of constantly visualizing success, routinely imagine the negative consequences of failing to reach your goal. Specifically thinking about what could go wrong or how you’ll feel if you fail helps keep you driven and focused.
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s a near doubling in the probability of reaching one&apos;s goal if you focus routinely on foreshadowing failure, you think about the ways in which things could fail...the more specific you can get by writing down or thinking about or talking about how bad it will be if you don&apos;t achieve your goals, the more likely you are to achieve those goals.&quot;</p>
<h2>Break Down Goals Into Milestones and Assess Weekly  </h2>
To leverage your brain’s dopamine system, set concrete milestones between now and your ultimate goal, and review your progress at regular intervals, like once a week. This approach keeps motivation high and helps correct your course as you go.
<p>&gt; &quot;I think that checking in at the end of a week, looking back on the previous week, and assessing how well you performed in pursuit of a given goal or how many times you did something that you wanted to do or avoided something that you didn&apos;t want to do...is a reasonable and tractable schedule to assess once a week.&quot;</p>
<h2>Practice Space-Time Bridging for Flexible Focus  </h2>
Use the “space-time bridging” practice to train shifting your attention from your internal state to increasingly distant visual targets and back, using cycles of three slow breaths at each focal point (internal sensation, your body, a mid-distance point, a distant horizon, and wide panoramic view, then return). This exercise helps you flexibly align your focus with immediate tasks or long-term goals.
<p>&gt; &quot;What you first do is you would close your eyes and you would focus as much of your attention including your visual attention on your inner landscape...Then you would open your eyes and you would focus your visual attention on some area on the surface of your body...then...to outside my body to some location in the room...then further away...then return immediately to my internal landscape...The entire thing takes about 90 seconds to 3 minutes depending on how many breaths you do.&quot;</p>
<h2>Understand and Harness Dopamine as Motivation  </h2>
Dopamine is not just for pleasure, but is the key chemical for motivation and effort toward goals. Even a small reward or an unexpected win spikes dopamine and renews drive, while failing to reach an expected outcome causes a drop and disappointment—knowing this, set up your milestones and little wins to keep momentum.
<p>&gt; &quot;Dopamine is the common currency by which we assess our progress toward particular things of particular value...Dopamine really sits at the heart of our motivational state to seek out goals and to seek pleasure...The biggest increases in dopamine are response to things that are positive and unexpected.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Behavioral Tools to Train Motivation and Focus  </h2>
Prioritize behavioral strategies like visual focusing and shifting attention before relying on supplements or chemicals to boost motivation, because building these habits actually makes your attention and drive systems stronger over time through neuroplasticity.
<p>&gt; &quot;Behavioral tools used over time engage neuroplasticity. As we start to practice using our visual system to harness our attention...we get better and better at using those systems. In fact, the systems for focus and motivation themselves have plasticity.&quot;</p>
<h2>Plan Concrete Actions Toward Your Goal  </h2>
List specific steps you will take to reach your goal instead of relying on vague intentions. Concrete action plans enhance your likelihood of consistent progress and allow for clear weekly self-assessment and milestone setting.
<p>&gt; &quot;Second, plan concretely. You need a concrete set of actions that you&apos;re going to follow in order to reach your goals.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] 23 Lessons from 2025]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2NjN6W8cnIg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-8</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:02:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2NjN6W8cnIg">23 Lessons from 2025</a></h1>
<h2>Reflect on Both Sides of Your Inheritance</h2>
<p>When reviewing how your upbringing affected you, be honest about where your strengths come from—not just your struggles. The same tough circumstances that created challenges often forged positive traits. For personal growth, trace your strengths and wounds back to their roots, and stop blaming others for all your flaws while claiming all your virtues as your own.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;If you are going to draw a straight line from your childhood to your flaws, you should trace that same lineage to your strengths. If you can’t let your parents take credit for what&apos;s right with you, maybe you shouldn&apos;t be so quick to make them the villains for what’s wrong.&quot;</p>
<h2>Be Discerning With Self-Help Advice</h2>
<p>Not all advice is for you. Guidance tends to amplify what&apos;s already strong in you, rather than correcting your weaknesses. Reflect on what you truly need instead of taking advice that just confirms your existing tendencies—and beware of becoming an “advice hyperresponder.”</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Advice doesn’t land evenly. It finds the path of least resistance and tends to be absorbed by people who already lean in its direction... Good counsel when misapplied can be worse than bad counsel or none at all. The resistant ignore it while the receptive overdo it.&quot;</p>
<h2>Vulnerability Is Real Strength</h2>
<p>Embracing emotions and showing vulnerability is an act of true courage, not a sign of weakness. Strength is found in honestly expressing yourself and facing your feelings, which deepens your relationships and promotes authenticity. Suppressing feelings is avoidance, not resilience.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Resilience is about people who feel their feelings deeply but are able to act despite them in their best interests... Vulnerability is being scared of speaking your truth and doing it anyway. It&apos;s choosing presence before protection.&quot;</p>
<h2>Single-Task Intensity Beats Scattered Effort</h2>
<p>Commit deeply to one goal at a time for meaningful progress. Multitasking or spreading yourself thin leads to mediocrity and stagnation. Short, intense periods of focus yield far greater results than years of half-hearted effort.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;You will make more progress in 6 months of dedicated training than in 2 years of half-in half-out training. And you will learn more... That&apos;s the unlock.&quot;</p>
<h2>Procrastination Masks Fear, Not Laziness</h2>
<p>If you’re putting things off, you might be protecting your self-worth—not just wasting time. Ask yourself what you&apos;re really afraid of, and take tiny steps rather than focusing on the big scary task. Let yourself be a beginner, accept possible failure, and move forward anyway.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;On the surface, procrastination looks like laziness, but underneath it&apos;s fear wearing a pajama top... You don’t need courage to begin. You just need the willingness to be seen beginning.&quot;</p>
<h2>Focus on Outcomes, Not Just Effort or Output</h2>
<p>Measure achievement by real-world results, not just by time spent (inputs) or tasks completed (outputs). Direct your energy toward outcomes that actually move you closer to your goals, and regularly check if your actions are truly effective.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Busy people count hours and actions. Effective people count impact. If you measure inputs, you’ll get good at trying... But if you measure outcomes, you’ll get good at winning.&quot;</p>
<h2>Relationship Red Flags & Success Traits</h2>
<p>For strong long-term relationships, seek partners who are agreeable, conscientious, and moderately open to new experiences. Recognize early warning signs—like consistent disregard for your feelings or avoidance of accountability—and remember it&apos;s handling difficulties, not just sharing good times, that predicts lasting happiness.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;The divorce mystery... good times are a poor predictor of how you’ll handle bad times and handling bad times is much more important to the success of a marriage.&quot;</p>
<h2>Authenticity and Self-Respect in Relationships</h2>
<p>True intimacy is only possible if you show up as your full self. Don’t hide or shape-shift just to please your partner; prioritizing their opinion over your self-worth leads to neediness and self-rejection, eroding the relationship long term.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Every time you show up as someone else to please another person, you’re rejecting yourself... True intimacy is being radically unedited and still accepted and the rest is just set design.&quot;</p>
<h2>Embrace the Reality of Small Fears—Don’t Shame Yourself</h2>
<p>Modern anxieties may seem trivial compared to dangers of the past, but your nervous system reacts the same way. Let go of the guilt for feeling fear; recognize your struggles as legitimate, and treat yourself kindly when you’re uncomfortable.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Your nervous system does not care whether the threat is a bear or a boundary. It reacts in the same way. So be gentle with yourself if you get scared by normal stuff.&quot;</p>
<h2>Set Boundaries—You’re Not Responsible for Everyone</h2>
<p>Needing harmony can lead you to absorb blame that isn’t yours. True courage is recognizing what’s yours to own and returning responsibility to others when necessary. Refusing to carry everyone’s burdens is essential for healthy relationships and self-esteem.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;If you care too much about harmony, you end up volunteering to be the scapegoat in every room... Bravery isn’t bowing your head. It’s lifting it and saying, &apos;This one’s not on me.&apos;&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] How to Engineer a Life You Love - Mark Rober]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPnDeHKHAys</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-9</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 23:01:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sPnDeHKHAys">How to Engineer a Life You Love - Mark Rober</a></h1>
<h2>Embrace Failure as a Pathway to Success</h2>
<p>Understand that meaningful progress comes through iterative prototypes, embracing mistakes, and learning from what doesn’t work rather than aiming for perfection from the start. Apply a mindset of “failing forward” to projects, goals, and personal growth: make quick, rough attempts, intentionally break things, and improve based on direct experience. Don&apos;t internalize setbacks—treat them as necessary feedback loops.</p>
<p>&gt; “Failing is the goal. Like you want to break this thing. So if I know I have to design the wheels for the rover… I&apos;m going to make them out of three materials… I&apos;m going to test it and I&apos;m going to smash it. I&apos;m going to break it because now I&apos;m confident when I have my final answer, I know exactly why it is and the full limits of it, like what it&apos;s capable of.”</p>
<h2>Gamify Challenges and Reframe Failure</h2>
<p>Boost motivation by approaching real-life setbacks like video game challenges: see each attempt as an opportunity to learn rather than evidence of ineptitude. Focus on incremental improvement, detaching failure from personal identity, and keep your sights on the end goal. Use this mindset in everything from job searches and relationships to learning new skills.</p>
<p>&gt; “But in like video games, you know, if you pick up the controller and you go and you fall into a pit, you&apos;re not like, ‘Oh, I&apos;m bad at video games…’ Immediately you&apos;re like, ‘Oh, shoot. I want to try this again. Like, what did I learn?...’ You&apos;re excited because you&apos;re… focusing on the end goal.”</p>
<h2>Manage Dopamine and Avoid Burnout by Pacing Yourself</h2>
<p>To prevent burnout, set your work and ambitions to a “jogging pace” that is sustainable for the long run instead of sprinting endlessly after momentary rewards. Be intentional about your commitments, avoid overwhelming complexity, and recognize the natural decline in satisfaction after big achievements. Prioritize focus and moderation across pursuits, and be conscious of motivation cycles to maintain long-term enthusiasm.</p>
<p>&gt; “...one thing I really try and do is like keep my treadmill at like a jogging pace. Like I can do this… And I&apos;ve just kind of like tortoise in the hair of this thing. And now 14 years later… still going and still stoked and like I&apos;m as far away from burnout as… ever been.”</p>
<h2>Use Prototyping and Iterative Design in Everyday Problem Solving</h2>
<p>Apply engineering principles to personal and professional projects by breaking large goals into smaller chunks. Start with rough versions (“prototypes”), test them without worrying about polish, and use failures as data for improvement. This reduces overwhelm and increases your chance of success whether you’re building, learning, or planning something new.</p>
<p>&gt; “The number one mistake people make when they try and make something is… they try and make the final version first… As opposed to… prototypes. You just do a something quick and dirty first… and you learn from them… and failing is the goal.”</p>
<h2>Capture and Maintain Attention for Effective Learning</h2>
<p>Whether teaching kids or adults, prioritize generating curiosity and emotional engagement before delivering content. Use visual demonstrations, stories, or unexpected actions to earn attention, and then anchor lessons or messages to that emotional hook. If you can earn attention and spark fun or wonder, learning follows naturally.</p>
<p>&gt; “Every teacher will tell you like I can&apos;t teach you if I don&apos;t have your attention and I think they do a very bad job of getting kids attention… If it&apos;s fun now, we&apos;ll figure out how to attach the learning on to that. So start with the attention and a lot of times that comes with fun.”</p>
<h2>Channel Curiosity and Hands-On Tinkering, Even as an Adult</h2>
<p>Make time for activities that challenge you to create, build, or experiment with your own hands. Doing things slowly or for their own sake (rather than always seeking efficiency or improvement) can rekindle joy, creativity, and resilience—combatting the effects of information overload and passive consumption.</p>
<p>&gt; “I feel like we are drowning inputs and sort of starved for outputs… actually doing something with our own hands. That time is now just like passively feed my brain and you can only learn… But you haven&apos;t constructed anything on the other side.”</p>
<h2>Collaborate for Impact: Combine Technical Skill and Emotional Intelligence</h2>
<p>Sustained, meaningful achievements require not just technical expertise but also the ability to communicate, collaborate, and inspire others around a shared vision. Invest in your ability to evoke emotion, tell compelling stories, and convey the “why” behind your goals within teams, workplaces, or creative projects.</p>
<p>&gt; “...what makes our species… different… is our ability to collaborate at large scales and have shared goals and that happens through stories that usually are fictional but… you share a vision… at Apple I did find people… were better communicators across the board… and that is almost… equally important.”</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] How to get rich with stocks (without math, charts or models)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rdChG9FPs80</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-10</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:00:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rdChG9FPs80">How to get rich with stocks (without math, charts or models)</a></h1>
<h2>Observational Investing: The Edge for “Outsiders”</h2>
Spotting real-world changes—like behavior shifts, cultural trends, or new product buzz—before Wall Street catches on gives individual investors a practical edge. If you use social channels, comments, or your own life observations to uncover information others are missing, you can make meaningful trades ahead of the herd.
<p>&gt; “You&apos;re looking for any change that&apos;s happening in the world, whether it&apos;s change in consumer behavior, culture, technology, weather, politics... If you can surface that change early and connect the dots back to a company that would benefit or be harmed by that change, that&apos;s essentially the entire methodology.”</p>
<h2>Use Social Platforms as Alpha Sources</h2>
Rather than relying solely on traditional financial data, trawl social media—especially comment sections and trends—to spot shifts in what people are interested in, buying, or talking about. This “conversational” data can signal opportunities long before hard numbers reflect them.
<p>&gt; “That&apos;s where I get most of my alpha from recently is people, because that&apos;s just happens to be the place where people express themselves most freely across the largest number of topics.”</p>
<h2>Focus on Information Asymmetry, Not Valuation</h2>
Don’t obsess over stock price, valuation ratios, or technical charts. Instead, invest when you know something important that most people (and the market) haven’t recognized yet—and exit when that insight becomes common knowledge.
<p>&gt; “Ideally, you&apos;d be completely blind to stock price, completely blind to everything other than the extent to which other investors were aware of that one thing that you surface… you enter your position at the point of information asymmetry... and you exit at the point of information parity.”</p>
<h2>Build “Big Money” Risk Capital Buckets</h2>
Separate your main savings from a dedicated “risk” account. Fund this with small sacrifices (like making your own coffee or clipping coupons), then use this capital to make high-conviction, possibly leveraged bets. This psychological and financial separation helps you swing big when you discover a unique opportunity—while avoiding risking your core savings.
<p>&gt; “Everybody should have a big money account. And the big money account is the account that yes, you get wealthy quickly with. And you do that by taking big swings on things that you really believe in... you fund that big account with money that is not being stolen from other areas of your life.”</p>
<h2>Do Deep, Comprehensive Research Before Major Trades</h2>
If you’re making a large or leveraged bet based on an observation, supplement your insight with rigorous research—use all sources, even travel or direct store visits, to avoid missing key details or blind spots.
<p>&gt; “I take a lot of pride in going in deep and doing really intense comprehensive due diligence, where sometimes if I have a high conviction trade, I will put 60 plus hours of due diligence into the trade...”</p>
<h2>Learn from Losses and Manage Risk Aggressively</h2>
Even high-conviction observations can go wrong, so calculate position sizing (typically 5–10% of your liquid portfolio per trade) and be ready for losses. Surviving a major setback requires both emotional resilience and sticking to your research-driven process.
<p>&gt; “Percentage wise, when you have a high conviction idea, I&apos;m usually investing between 5 and 10% of my entire liquid portfolio into that idea via options... I lost a third of my portfolio on a single trade... but still found a way... to actually still go all in on my thesis.”</p>
<h2>Institutional Wall Street Is Slow to Adopt New Data—That’s Your Chance</h2>
Large funds mostly rely on historic, correlated transactional data (like credit card receipts), making them slower to react to new conversational or cultural trends. As a nimble individual, you can spot and act on genuine shifts faster, especially in overlooked market corners.
<p>&gt; “Wall Street... like correlated data. They like certainty... The data that I am trading is conversational data because Wall Street primarily uses transactional data... So, how do we gain an edge on a hedge fund... Well, what do you do before you buy something? You talk about buying it.”</p>
<h2>Apply Observational Investing Beyond Stocks</h2>
This skill isn’t limited to public equity trading—use it to identify new business opportunities and guide your career choices by tracking real-world shifts and trends, not just fixed paths.
<p>&gt; “The same methodology of being able to identify change in the world and tailwinds and trends should apply to career. It should also apply to entrepreneurs... these are some of the biggest decisions of your life. It&apos;s not just about trading a stock.”</p>
<h2>Don’t Be Afraid to Violate Conventional Investment Wisdom</h2>
You don’t have to be a Wall Street insider, have elite credentials, or follow conventional buy-and-hold or valuation-centric strategies. Outsiders can succeed by thinking and researching differently, so don’t let traditional wisdom limit your approach.
<p>&gt; “I graduated in the bottom 25% of my high school class. The bottom 20... I am not a proponent of people quitting their jobs and becoming entrepreneurs... I think this roadmap is way more achievable for people... Because you can do this.”</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] Transform Pain & Trauma Into Creative Expression | David Choe]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zHyvVajsqMw</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-11</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:01:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zHyvVajsqMw">Transform Pain &amp; Trauma Into Creative Expression | David Choe</a></h1>
<h2>Embrace Vulnerability to Heal Shame and Find Connection  </h2>
Opening up about your struggles and vulnerabilities can transform shame into connection, creativity, and self-acceptance. Sharing your real experiences encourages others to connect and do the same, leading to personal growth.
<p>&gt; &quot;But if I can meet another spirit or soul and you&apos;re...if you share with me your heart, then it&apos;s a shared brokenness.&quot;</p>
<h2>Recognize and Address the Roots of Addiction  </h2>
Understanding that addiction is often an attempt to escape pain or self-hatred lets you address the underlying issues instead of just the surface behavior. Pay attention to what you’re running from, and seek help to sit with those uncomfortable feelings rather than act out compulsively.
<p>&gt; &quot;People, what are you running from, Dave? It&apos;s like, well, I&apos;m running from myself, dude. I don&apos;t want to look in the mirror.&quot;</p>
<h2>Redefine Success: Thrive, Don’t Just Survive  </h2>
It’s not enough to simply make it through life; focus on practices that allow you to enjoy and take pride in living, not just surviving your hardships. Ask yourself if you’re actually having fun and what it takes to move from just surviving to truly thriving.
<p>&gt; &quot;I don&apos;t want to survive. I want to thrive. Right. …are we having fun yet? Like isn&apos;t aren&apos;t we supposed to have fun?&quot;</p>
<h2>Practice Self-Affirmation and Rewriting Personal Narratives  </h2>
Use daily self-affirmations and intentional “brainwashing” to replace negative internalized stories with more empowering beliefs about yourself. Actions as simple as posting affirmations in your space can reshape your focus toward self-worth.
<p>&gt; &quot;Why can&apos;t I brainwash myself into thinking I&apos;m a good person?...I am worthy. I am enough.&quot;</p>
<h2>Accept Imperfection and the Messy Path to Growth  </h2>
Let go of the pressure for everything to be perfect or for your journey to be linear; progress often looks messy and nonlinear. Having the courage to show up as you are—imperfect, unfiltered, and growing—creates authentic, lasting transformation.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s going to be me. It&apos;s going to be sloppy. …progress, not perfection, right?&quot;</p>
<h2>Find Power in Adaptability and Surrender  </h2>
Life demands flexibility—the willingness to change direction, try new things, and surrender control when needed. You may need to move on from what once worked and approach new problems with a different attitude.
<p>&gt; &quot;My mom taught me…just adapt. Oh, our business just burned down in the LA Riots. And instead of like sitting there, it&apos;s like, &apos;Okay, now we&apos;re doing this.&apos;&quot;</p>
<h2>Action Beats Overthinking When Dealing with Difficult Feelings  </h2>
You can’t think your way out of pain or emotional challenges; doing, expressing, or creating is often more effective than ruminating or attempting to logic your way through.
<p>&gt; &quot;You&apos;re never going to outthink a feeling. You&apos;re never going to outsmart a feeling…It&apos;s not logical. It&apos;s an emotional thing.&quot;</p>
<h2>Protect and Prioritize Your Mental Health by Limiting Stimuli  </h2>
Modern life, especially digital addiction, can worsen anxiety and compulsive behaviors. Take active steps to block or limit access to technology and build in quiet time to reflect and recharge.
<p>&gt; &quot;…it would be impossible for me to get anything done if I didn&apos;t go out of my way to block all my electronic devices.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] The Best Moments of Modern Wisdom (2025)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8LBLLC5JvaA</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-12</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:01:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8LBLLC5JvaA">The Best Moments of Modern Wisdom (2025)</a></h1>
<h2>Build Self-Esteem by Living Up to Your Own Standards  </h2>
Improving your self-esteem starts with living in alignment with your personal values and moral code. You should take pride in making sacrifices for others and fulfilling your duties, as these acts of love and service build a deeper internal reputation. When facing low self-worth, commit to explicitly identifying your values and holding yourself accountable to them.
<p>&gt; &quot;Self-esteem is a reputation you have with yourself … If you don’t live up to your own moral code, the same code that you hold others to, it will damage your self-esteem.&quot;</p>
<h2>Focus on What You Can Control and Savor the Present  </h2>
Continually dwelling on what's missing or on things you can't control is a recipe for ongoing dissatisfaction. To sustain happiness and lower stress, direct your attention to the present and the specific actions you can take—shift your thinking from lack to gratitude and from rumination to action.
<p>&gt; &quot;We don&apos;t experience life. We experience the part of life we focus on. And ... if you&apos;re always focused on missing, how can you sustain happiness?&quot;</p>
<h2>The Value of Action: Small Steps Build Momentum  </h2>
If you’re feeling overwhelmed or anxious, break your goal into the smallest possible step, then take immediate action—this generates positive momentum, confidence, and motivation, even when you don't feel like it. Overthinking or waiting for perfect conditions creates paralysis; progress comes from movement.
<p>&gt; &quot;Action is the antidote to anxiety ... You really don&apos;t fear the future when you&apos;re moving yourself toward it.&quot;</p>
<h2>Choose Sincerity Over Perfection to Foster Connection  </h2>
Show up authentically in conversations and relationships, even if you're scared of rejection or feeling exposed. Sincerity, playfulness, and open-hearted effort deepen relationships and build true connection, while hiding behind a persona or trying to please people at the cost of authenticity leads to resentment and insecurity.
<p>&gt; &quot;If I say the important thing to you and I&apos;m vulnerable with you, our connection deepens.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Your Inner Critic Constructively  </h2>
Harness your self-doubt by turning vague criticism into specific, actionable feedback for growth. Treat your inner critic as a helpful coach rather than a harsh judge by asking, “What, exactly, can I improve?” and then focus on the process of iteration instead of ruminating on failure.
<p>&gt; &quot;How about we get away from the vague critic and we move toward the specific coach with regards to this.&quot;</p>
<h2>Take Responsibility for Your Response to Uncertainty and Anxiety  </h2>
When anxiety strikes, recognize it as an alarm signaling that you’ve disconnected from your own power. Respond by grounding yourself in the present, remembering your capacity to adapt, and focusing on practical steps you can take right now rather than spiraling into “what if” scenarios.
<p>&gt; &quot;All anxiety is separation anxiety ... It’s not separation from another person. It’s separation from self.&quot;</p>
<h2>Seek Playful, Iterative Improvement Rather Than Perfection  </h2>
There is no end state of “done” or “perfect”—there’s only the ongoing process of experimentation, learning, and adjusting. Embrace iteration and evolution in both personal growth and work, and accept that every new step is part of the journey.
<p>&gt; &quot;There is no way of getting it perfect. There is no complete, no finish line, no done. There is simply what&apos;s the next experiment.&quot;</p>
<h2>High-Agency Thinking: Break Problems Down and Question Constraints  </h2>
To get unstuck, ask if your limits are truly absolute or just social constructs. Break big challenges into very small, achievable steps (the "video game level one" approach) and question accepted constraints by asking, “Does this actually defy the laws of physics?”
<p>&gt; &quot;As long as it doesn&apos;t defy the laws of physics, anything is … theoretically possible with human knowledge.&quot;</p>
<h2>Don’t Neglect Structure and Discipline's Role in Well-being  </h2>
If you’re drifting or feeling lost, restore daily structure through simple routines like regular meals, exercise, or other scheduled commitments. Structure builds the foundation for renewed life satisfaction and motivation, especially when large goals disappear or circumstances change.
<p>&gt; &quot;What has made me feel better recently was working out again on a schedule and eating five meals a day … having that little bit of structure.&quot;</p>
<h2>Honest, Virtuous Example Overrides Words—Especially for Parents  </h2>
The most effective way to teach children or influence others is to model the virtues and behaviors you hope to see in them. Words matter less than lived example; living with integrity and showing love directly shapes those around you.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you want to teach virtue, practice virtue. Be the person you want your kids to actually turn into and they will become that.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] Essentials: How to Optimize Your Hormones for Health & Vitality | Dr. Kyle Gillett]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fYhY-vC000A</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-13</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:01:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fYhY-vC000A">Essentials: How to Optimize Your Hormones for Health &amp; Vitality | Dr. Kyle Gillett</a></h1>
<h2>The Six Pillars of Hormone Health</h2>
To optimize hormone health throughout life, consistently focus on the six pillars: diet, exercise (especially resistance training), stress management, sleep optimization, sunlight/outdoor exposure, and spiritual well-being. Long-term consistency in small lifestyle interventions matters more than extreme diets or routines.
<p>&gt; &quot;The law of diminishing returns applies. So, doing a little amount of what I call lifestyle interventions over a long period of time is going to be far more helpful or efficacious than doing a lot and then doing nothing. So, I talk about the big six pillars... The two strongest ones are likely diet and exercise for hormone health.&quot;</p>
<h2>Individualize Diet and Exercise for Better Outcomes</h2>
There is no one-size-fits-all diet. Pay attention to your body’s feedback or consider genetic testing to guide food choices, and aim for a minimum of 150–180 minutes of zone 2 cardio weekly. Your personalized approach supports optimal hormone balance.
<p>&gt; &quot;Yeah, diet should be an individualized approach... you can use your BOF feedback, how you&apos;re feeling to guess what you tolerate well, or you can just get genetic testing... almost everybody should or everybody should be getting 150 to 180 minutes minimum of zone 2 cardio per week.&quot;</p>
<h2>Understand When Caloric Restriction Helps or Hurts</h2>
Caloric restriction (including intermittent fasting) benefits those with obesity or metabolic syndrome by improving testosterone and metabolic health, but can reduce testosterone in healthy, lean individuals. Always assess your health status and goals before restricting calories.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you&apos;re obese or you have metabolic syndrome, caloric restriction will improve your testosterone... if you&apos;re young and healthy and you don&apos;t have metabolic syndrome, then caloric restriction will likely decrease your testosterone.&quot;</p>
<h2>Regular and Targeted Blood Testing</h2>
Routine blood testing every 3–6 months—both fasting and non-fasting—can help spot potential hormonal issues early and guide your health choices, especially if you notice symptoms like changes in energy, focus, libido, or athletic performance.
<p>&gt; &quot;Every 3 to 6 months for preventative purposes. You should also get a blood test when you&apos;re fasting and when you&apos;re not fasting.&quot;</p>
<h2>Manage DHT and Hair Loss Without Broad Systemic Effects</h2>
For those concerned about hair loss but wishing to avoid the broader negative effects of systemic DHT inhibitors, ask your doctor about localized treatments such as topical or injected dutasteride mesotherapy for the scalp.
<p>&gt; &quot;The most promising is called dutasteride misotherapy. Essentially, what it is is it&apos;s very localized injections in areas that are prone to male pattern baldness... it acts locally only and you repeat these injections from time to time.&quot;</p>
<h2>Recognize and Address PCOS Symptoms Early</h2>
PCOS is common and often underdiagnosed; symptoms include androgen excess (acne, excess hair, hair loss), insulin resistance, and menstrual irregularities. Early intervention through lifestyle changes or, if necessary, medications like metformin or inositol can help manage symptoms and fertility.
<p>&gt; &quot;PCOS is polycystic ovarian syndrome and this is one of those conditions which is underdiagnosed... If you have androgenic acne, if you have hair growth on the chin... more than 35day intervals in between a period... that can be a sign that you have oligo which means too little minora which means minces.&quot;</p>
<h2>Alcohol and Smoked Marijuana Lower Testosterone</h2>
High alcohol intake and smoking marijuana (but not cannabinoids like CBD or THC alone) can lower testosterone by increasing estrogen levels. Limiting these substances is wise for those concerned with hormone health.
<p>&gt; &quot;If it&apos;s smoked marijuana, then it&apos;s very likely to increase your aromatase, which increases your estrogen and... that&apos;s going to decrease testosterone... As far as alcohol, high alcohol will decrease testosterone as will any very potent GABA agonist.&quot;</p>
<h2>Peptide Use Requires Medical Oversight</h2>
Interest in peptides is rising, but only use them under a doctor’s direction and source from reputable compounding pharmacies to avoid harmful contaminants like LPS (lipopolysaccharide). Avoid peptides that may increase cancer risk or are not FDA-approved.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you&apos;re interested in peptides, you absolutely need to work with a physician in my opinion. Get it from a really good compounding pharmacy who will clean out the LPS... if you have cancer or a high cancer risk, you probably don&apos;t want to be taking a medication that&apos;s the exact opposite mechanism of action as your essential anti-cancer med.&quot;</p>
<h2>Integrate Physical, Mental, and Spiritual Health</h2>
Don’t compartmentalize your health; instead, understand that physical, mental, and spiritual well-being are deeply interconnected. Actively address your spiritual health in a way that fits your beliefs for optimal overall health.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s like a vin diagram and you have a body and a mind and a soul and you can&apos;t have one healthy without the other healthy... if that piece is not there, then that&apos;s going to affect your body physiologically as well.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] Life Hacks: A Christmas Special (2025)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hLIvhTiytIE</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-14</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:01:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hLIvhTiytIE">Life Hacks: A Christmas Special (2025)</a></h1>
<h2>Make Meditation a Daily Habit with the Right Buy-in</h2>
Committing to daily meditation is easier if you first find a compelling reason or framework that changes your perspective on it. Using introductory content, like the "fundamentals" series in the Waking Up app, can shift meditation from a chore to an integrated part of your identity. Keeping sessions short (e.g., 10 minutes) lowers the barrier to starting and maintaining the habit.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s kind of like the switch where you go from like going to the gym because you think you should to it just becomes like part of your personality, part of what you do. And that identity change for me was that series.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Uber and Flighty for Effortless Travel Planning</h2>
Simplify your travel routine by booking flights directly through Uber, which streamlines booking and handles all your details, plus gives credits. Use the Flighty app to automatically track flights, get real-time updates faster than airport boards, and aggregate all your trip details without stress.
<p>&gt; &quot;I booked my next flight to Vietnam on Uber on mobile. It&apos;s like it already has your details and you just go book done... Flighty is a flight tracking app... it automatically loads everything in and it tells you gate changes, delays, where your luggage is going to, what terminal you leave from...&quot;</p>
<h2>Boost Deep Work by Actively Tracking Focus Time</h2>
Use a chess clock, timer, or similar tool to accurately track actual periods of focused work. Each time you are distracted—even briefly—stop or flip the timer. This creates awareness of your productive hours and discourages multitasking or self-deception about your work habits.
<p>&gt; &quot;Whenever you&apos;re doing anything that isn&apos;t the thing, you have to hit it over... if you can get four hours done in a day I think you&apos;re in the top 1%.&quot;</p>
<h2>Block Digital Distractions and Increase Friction</h2>
Leverage physical and digital aids to reduce phone usage and distractions. Tools like the 'brick' NFC device or timed lockboxes make it inconvenient to access apps or your phone, breaking the automatic habit of checking devices. Switching to analog tools like a Moleskin notepad can help channel attention and ideas while reducing digital temptations.
<p>&gt; &quot;You have to like go to where the thing is in the house, press unbrick and then tap the NFC device. It&apos;s just been the most effective thing... So having a Moleskin notepad is... you then that then begins to whisper to you. So... you take it out and you go for a walk, it&apos;s whispering, &apos;Oh, check page three.&apos;&quot;</p>
<h2>Reframe Envy: Compare the Full “War” Not Just the “Highlight Reel”</h2>
Before feeling envy toward someone's success, consider both their public achievements and all the hidden challenges or trade-offs they face. Adjust your perspective to only desire someone else's situation if you're willing to accept every aspect of their reality—not just the glamorous parts.
<p>&gt; &quot;Unless I&apos;ve seen the war, I&apos;m not envious. And if I see the war and I like it, I&apos;m willing to be Napoleon.&quot;</p>
<h2>Savor Ordinary Pleasures and Practice Gratitude</h2>
Make a conscious effort to appreciate simple, everyday pleasures—like health, friendship, or daily comforts—especially as these are the things you'll miss most with time. Periodically envision how your current life would seem to your older self or someone from the past to generate authentic gratitude.
<p>&gt; &quot;What would 80-year-old me have appreciated about my day today?... That&apos;s the stuff that I feel... pick the stuff you would ignore because it&apos;s the stuff that when you&apos;re 80 just won&apos;t be there anymore.&quot;</p>
<h2>Learn from the Unteachable: Accept That Some Lessons Require Experience</h2>
Recognize that certain insights in life—such as the limits of fame, wealth, or external achievement—cannot be understood secondhand and must be lived to be believed. This awareness can foster self-compassion for past choices and help set more realistic expectations for future goals.
<p>&gt; &quot;There are a particular category of insights about life that you cannot learn without experiencing. And money won&apos;t make you happy. Fame won&apos;t fix your self worth...&quot;</p>
<h2>Focus on Becoming, Not Just Achieving</h2>
Instead of measuring progress solely by results or milestones, shift your focus to the personal traits and character growth developed through pursuing your goals. The process of striving changes you more than any external outcome.
<p>&gt; &quot;The goals, I don&apos;t think they really compound... but the traits that you get from chasing the hard things is the compounding.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use “Deep Sparring” for Better Problem Solving</h2>
Regularly engage in honest, in-depth conversations with trusted peers or friends to work through challenges and exchange advice. This shared problem-solving dramatically boosts perspective and helps overcome self-doubt or tunnel vision.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s probably about three to five people in my life where we can sit down, go for dinner... and there&apos;s this... line of when I advise other people I gain 20 IQ points and when I advise myself I lose 20 IQ points.&quot;</p>
<h2>Increase Happiness by Bringing Positivity First</h2>
Shift your approach to life by assuming that how you feel is often reflected back to you by the world around you. Proactively choose your mindset and energy, knowing that what you project will often be returned.
<p>&gt; &quot;The mirror only smiles when you smile has been my mantra for the year... All you can do is bring the positive energy to it and then everything else reflects it back to you.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] A $20B Founder Tells the Truth About Building a Company]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hG96Z4U3l3o</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-15</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hG96Z4U3l3o">A $20B Founder Tells the Truth About Building a Company</a></h1>
<h2>Emotional Reality of Entrepreneurship: Embrace Uncertainty and Self-Doubt  </h2>
Running or founding a fast-growing company is emotionally taxing, and constant self-doubt and existential threat are normal—even as the company scales. Rather than waiting to feel secure, founders should accept that negative self-talk and imposter syndrome are widely shared among successful entrepreneurs and learn how to function despite them.
<p>&gt; &quot;I&apos;m the same. And people say, you know, you want to be very positive and positive and motivate the people. I tend to be paranoid. I still, after all these years, have imposter syndrome...Almost all of them. I interview all these CEOs and I ask them during the interviews, you know, do you have imposter syndrome?...Almost all of them.&quot;</p>
<h2>Company Growth Means Constant Change—Everything Breaks with Scale  </h2>
As your company grows fast, expect that every process, system, and aspect of operations will face breaking points. Plan for regular reinvention, proactive problem analysis, and learning from mistakes to keep up with scaling challenges.
<p>&gt; &quot;As you grow, if you&apos;re growing fast, everything breaks. You know, people break, processes break, systems break. Like everything&apos;s just breaking, breaking, breaking with scale.&quot;</p>
<h2>Stick With It: Progress Is Nonlinear and Setbacks Are Inevitable  </h2>
Entrepreneurs should view progress as two steps forward, one step back. Most setbacks are self-inflicted and can be valuable learning opportunities if analyzed honestly and acted upon, rather than reasons to give up.
<p>&gt; &quot;It was like two steps forward, one step back. It looks like, oh, if you look at the graphs, like, oh, that was an easy ride. It wasn&apos;t. Like, we had lots of issues and lots of problems and lots of setbacks along the way. And it&apos;s a little bit, I think what good entrepreneurs do is they just stick with it.&quot;</p>
<h2>Prioritize Building a Unique and Mission-Driven Culture Early  </h2>
A strong, differentiated company culture and clear mission help attract and retain top talent—especially in the early days. Focus on first principles, originality, and a shared commitment to a cause employees care about.
<p>&gt; &quot;We had a mission. The mission was to apply that idea to helping small businesses grow...Our culture, like you need to make a unique culture and you need to make a high quality culture. And if you do that, you pull and retain employees.&quot;</p>
<h2>Balance Founder Mode and Manager Mode; Don’t Over-Corporatize Too Early  </h2>
Founders should resist the pressure to become too managerial or corporate too quickly. Early founder-style management—direct feedback, many direct reports, decisive action—can be more effective than adopting “formal” management too soon.
<p>&gt; &quot;And I read the Founder Mode stuff. I&apos;m like, I should have stuck with my convictions on some of that stuff. I regret kind of, I got more Manager Mode-y as time went on. I regret that.&quot;</p>
<h2>Beware of “Big-Company” Hires and Overvaluing External Talent  </h2>
While it’s tempting to hire experienced executives from big corporations as your company grows, founders often undervalue their own homegrown talent. External hires can struggle to adapt, so prioritize promoting and investing in your existing people.
<p>&gt; &quot;And I think a mistake a lot of founders make is they go and hire that, whatever, CMO from Microsoft, whatever...And they&apos;re lost at C in this startup. And they&apos;re miserable. And their colleagues are miserable. So I see that as a big failure condition, particularly hiring people from much, much bigger companies.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Structured Reflection to Improve: The “Pothole Report”  </h2>
Implement a process to regularly analyze mistakes, identify warning signs missed, and document how similar issues can be prevented in the future. This systematic approach to learning from errors provides long-term value as your team scales.
<p>&gt; &quot;The pothole report was, every time we had a pothole, we&apos;d look back and like, how should we have handled this a year ago so that wouldn&apos;t have happened? Or what data do we wish we had?&quot;</p>
<h2>Assess Founders with the “FLOCK” Rubric  </h2>
When hiring or evaluating founders, consider: First-principled thinking, Lovability (would top talent work for them?), Obsession with the problem, Chip on their shoulder, and deep Knowledge of the field. Use these criteria to predict which startups are likely to attract resources and thrive.
<p>&gt; &quot;I came up with a thing I call flock. F is that when the founder pitches, you get the sense they&apos;re first principled in thinking, or they&apos;re just derivative in thinking. L is, are they lovable?...O is obsessed...C, I like the chip on the shoulder...and then are they deeply knowledgeable?&quot;</p>
<h2>Be Contrarian with Conviction—But Only When You’re Right  </h2>
Having the courage to pursue a contrarian thesis—such as focusing on SMBs when everyone pursues enterprise—can be a powerful differentiator if you’re right. Don’t change course just because of consensus resistance; conviction on key points is a valuable entrepreneurial asset.
<p>&gt; &quot;Peter Thiel has a line like, you need to be right about something that a lot of people disagree with. You need to be right about something that everyone thinks you&apos;re wrong about. And we had a couple of those. Not a lot, but we had a couple of important ones.&quot;</p>
<h2>Leveraging AI for Personal Productivity and Business Growth  </h2>
Personalized AI assistants—trained on your own data—offer huge productivity gains for knowledge work now, with rapid improvement expected. Start experimenting with tools like ChatGPT and Gemini to automate research, coaching, and daily decision support.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s incredibly valuable. These days, I just, I think, you know, I just came out with a new book, My Marketing Lesson, The Grateful Dead. We created a very, very cool set of videos around it that are AI generated...I feel like there&apos;s two of me already. I find it to be very helpful as like a daily coach and a therapist...&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] The Environmental Toxins Killing Your Health - Dr Gabrielle Lyon]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CZWrZVhU1O0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-16</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 23:01:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CZWrZVhU1O0">The Environmental Toxins Killing Your Health - Dr Gabrielle Lyon</a></h1>
<h2>Environment: The Overlooked Pillar of Health  </h2>
Beyond diet and exercise, environmental exposures like mold, parasites, heavy metals, and microplastics can have a significant, often hidden, impact on health. To address unexplained symptoms, consider your environment—where you live, the air you breathe, and your exposure to contaminants—as a potential root cause, especially when conventional tests come back normal.
<p>&gt; &quot;I had to call and apologize because it wasn&apos;t just diet and exercise. She had significant exposures that really affected her health and wellness. And I think these exposures affect a lot of people...&quot;</p>
<h2>Hidden Causes: Testing Gaps and Underdiagnosed Illness  </h2>
Common lab tests often miss complex environmental illnesses. If you have persistent, unexplained symptoms (fatigue, brain fog, rashes, joint pain), push for alternative diagnostics like microscopy for parasites or environmental assessments for mold, especially if initial tests come back "normal."
<p>&gt; &quot;People go to their doctor and get all of these blood panels done and everything looks quote perfect... when the reality is these are just a series of biomarkers... there is now a whole host of other influences that really end up affecting the way people show up in their lives...&quot;</p>
<h2>Mold and Parasite Exposure: Diagnosing and Managing  </h2>
Mold and parasite exposures are more common than many realize, especially with modern living and global food sourcing. Recognize vague symptoms (fatigue, digestive issues, rashes) as possible indicators, and don’t overlook transmission risks through partners, pets, or the environment. Testing may require more than standard procedures; old-school microscopy or specialty testing is sometimes needed.
<p>&gt; &quot;While we think that these parasites are easy to test for, and in theory they should be, I and many other providers are not seeing that in real life practice.&quot;</p>
<h2>Genetic Susceptibility to Environmental Triggers  </h2>
Not everyone is equally vulnerable to environmental exposures. If some people in your household get sick from mold or similar triggers while others don’t, genetic factors may be at play. Be proactive in identifying and mitigating environmental risks for the sensitive individuals.
<p>&gt; &quot;It seems as if there&apos;s a genetic component to those individuals that become affected versus those that are not. ...my son and myself are sensitive. My husband and my daughter are not...&quot;</p>
<h2>The Team Approach to Complex Illness  </h2>
If you’re struggling with unexplained or persistent symptoms, don't rely solely on a single doctor. Assemble a small, competent team—one main provider plus specialists—to dig deeper. Collaborative, cross-disciplinary care is critical for diagnosing and managing complex, multi-factorial health problems.
<p>&gt; &quot;Typically, it should be a core group, a handful of very competent individuals. Maybe it&apos;s three individuals. You have one quarterback and then you have individuals placed in various specialties.&quot;</p>
<h2>Removal First: Managing Environmental Illness  </h2>
The most important step in treating environmental illness is to remove yourself from the source—move out, avoid the contaminated food, filter your air. Even if inconvenient, this is often necessary for recovery, and it’s a concrete action that can make a big difference.
<p>&gt; &quot;Number one, remove yourself from the exposure. Understanding where you&apos;re living, you ha you have got to move. I&apos;m sorry, it&apos;s super inconvenient, but you cannot continue to be exposed to these things.&quot;</p>
<h2>Sauna and Detox Protocols for Recovery  </h2>
Sauna therapy (30–60 minutes, 113–176°F, under physician guidance) is supported by evidence for helping excrete fat-soluble toxins and reducing inflammation. Consider regular sauna sessions, and supplement with practices like using binders or infrared saunas if traditional saunas are not tolerated.
<p>&gt; &quot;With sauna protocols... this is a way for lipohilic chemicals so the chemicals that are stored in fats to be released through the skin excretion of these organic solvents.&quot;</p>
<h2>Mindset and Belief in Healing  </h2>
Your mindset significantly impacts recovery from complex illness. Develop and maintain conviction that you can improve; those who believe in their ability to heal tend to recover better, while persistent negative thinking can stall progress even if the right protocols are in place.
<p>&gt; &quot;If they do not believe that they will get better it&apos;s it is nearly impossible because now what&apos;s happening is you are fighting against your own physiology...&quot;</p>
<h2>Rethinking Diagnostic Markers and Medical Standards  </h2>
Don’t accept “normal labs” as a final answer if symptoms persist. Encourage your healthcare team to look for new or alternative biomarkers and stay open to emerging areas of research (e.g., muscle quality vs. body fat, environmental influences). Medicine needs to evolve beyond standard algorithms to address modern, complex conditions.
<p>&gt; &quot;If the lab values don&apos;t show, then we&apos;re not looking at the right labs. Period. End of story.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] Defining Healthy Masculinity & How to Build It | Terry Real]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qGb7hYMlA3o</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-17</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 23:01:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qGb7hYMlA3o">Defining Healthy Masculinity &amp; How to Build It | Terry Real</a></h1>
<h2>Relational Skills Are Essential for Men's Well-Being</h2>
<p>Building strong relationships—with partners, friends, or oneself—is not just &quot;nice to have&quot; but central to a man&apos;s mental health, happiness, and confidence. Learn to treat relating as a skill to be practiced, not an inborn trait. Prioritize connection and vulnerability over self-sufficiency or emotional detachment.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What will make us men healthy is connection. So, yeah, great. Have your feelings. And then what are you going to do with them?... The way we connect is through vulnerability.&quot;</p>
<h2>Emotional Expression Must Be Collaborative and Skilled</h2>
<p>Men should allow themselves to feel their emotions but must avoid dumping them on others or seeking to be rescued emotionally. Instead, emotional expression should be mutual and negotiated, asking for help without demanding it, and reciprocating support.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What I want men to move beyond is our selfishness... recovering feeling being stoic or having feelings. Sure. That&apos;s good. That&apos;s important. The way we connect is through feelings. The way we connect is through vulnerability.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Art of Repair: How to Handle Conflict Constructively</h2>
<p>Disruptions and arguments happen in all relationships, but being able to pause, reflect, and return to connection quickly is a core relationship skill. Take space when heated, contract for breaks in advance, and always return to fix things together.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;All relationships are an endless rhythm of closeness, disruption, and a return... We don&apos;t learn the skills of moving from disillusionment distance disruption back into repair and return.&quot;</p>
<h2>From Criticism to Request: Communicate What You Need Clearly</h2>
<p>Rather than focusing on complaints or character attacks, practice flipping every criticism into a clear, actionable request about what you want or need from the other person. This approach greatly increases the chances of positive change and connection.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;For every complaint, I want 99 requests instead... Inside of every complaint is a request. Think about that.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Crisis of Male Loneliness—And Why Men Need Fraternity</h2>
<p>Men of all ages suffer when they lack meaningful friendships or male groups. Seek out or create spaces—such as men&apos;s groups, sports teams, or even just regular activities with friends—where you can be open and support each other&apos;s growth.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;The crisis of men being alone and not having other men to support them and share is one of the great problems in modern society... I teach men to experiment and to try and drive their relationships deeper by sharing more and seeing what they get.&quot;</p>
<h2>Build Healthy Self-Esteem from the Inside, Not Performance</h2>
<p>Men often tie their self-worth to external achievements, making them prone to shame and defensiveness when things go wrong. Practice holding yourself in &quot;warm regard&quot; even when you make mistakes, and respond to feedback with accountability rather than shame or avoidance.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Self-esteem comes from the inside out. I have worth because I&apos;m here and I&apos;m breathing... The capacity to feel proportionally bad about bad behavior. I screwed up. I hurt you. I&apos;m sorry. And at the same time, hold yourself in warm regard as the imperfect person.&quot;</p>
<h2>Connection Is the Antidote to Addiction and Numbing Behaviors</h2>
<p>Habits such as substance abuse, excessive screen time, or seeking intensity stem from loneliness and disconnection. Prioritize building real intimacy and community—these are the true cures for compulsive behaviors and feelings of emptiness.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What we self-medicate when we self-medicate is the pain of disconnection. And the cure for addiction is intimacy... Relational connection is what we&apos;re born for.&quot;</p>
<h2>Emotional Flexibility: The Mark of a Whole Man</h2>
<p>True strength is being able to be fierce when needed and deeply tender when appropriate. Aim for adaptability—know when to stand firm and when to soften. Cultivate both courage and vulnerability.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;When the moment calls for fierceness, a good Morirani is a killer... When the moment calls for tenderness, a good Morani will lay down his sword and shield and be sweet like a baby... What makes a great Morani is knowing which moment is which.&quot;</p>
<h2>Treat Yourself and Others with Kindness, Not Harshness</h2>
<p>End harsh self-criticism. Treat yourself (and others) firmly but always kindly; harshness does nothing that loving firmness cannot do better. This self-compassion will spill outward, improving every relationship.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There is no redeeming value in harshness. Let me say it again. There is nothing that harshness does that loving firmness doesn&apos;t do better. Be firm but with love, not harshness. And that&apos;s you treating others. That&apos;s the way you allow others to treat you. And very much that&apos;s the way you treat you.&quot;</p>
<h2>Cultivate Relational Joy and Unstructured Togetherness</h2>
<p>Plan for unstructured, low-pressure time with loved ones—whether it&apos;s hanging out, listening to music, or family game nights. These moments foster connection and lasting happiness more than intense or &quot;optimized&quot; activities.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Families operate in the interstices... One of the things that families can teach us about relationality, relational joy, is hanging out, being it... The best stuff is the stuff that you would never post on social media because it&apos;s so boring for the internet and so awesome in real life.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] How to Stop Wasting Your Life - Connor Beaton]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3MZqj2COk68</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-18</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 23:01:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3MZqj2COk68">How to Stop Wasting Your Life - Connor Beaton</a></h1>
<h2>The Hidden Cost of Suppression in High-Performing Men</h2>
Suppressing emotions and weaknesses in pursuit of external success can lead to destructive behaviors and psychological exhaustion. For healthier outcomes, high-performing men should regularly acknowledge and address their anxieties and insecurities rather than medicating through maladaptive habits. Opening up about personal struggles, even just to oneself or a trusted confidant, creates a crucial release valve and prevents internal collapse.
<p>&gt; &quot;For high performing men that is way overindexed right so it&apos;s I need to develop competency capability strength...But I&apos;m going to do that by suppressing the unsavory parts of myself...And there&apos;s a cost to that suppression.&quot;</p>
<h2>Shame as a Motivator: Useful, But With Limits</h2>
Using shame or pain as motivation can propel achievement in the short term, but relying on it without developing self-recognition and self-compassion eventually results in burnout or emotional collapse. To prevent this, balance drive with tools for self-appreciation and the ability to celebrate accomplishments genuinely.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s not necessarily a bad thing to allow pain or shame to drive us and to motivate us... However, it has a shelf life. And if we don&apos;t develop the tools that are meant to go in tandem with it, it&apos;s always destined to fail.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Importance of Emotional Literacy and Regulation</h2>
Learning to identify, feel, and regulate one’s emotions is an essential skill for mental well-being and strong relationships. Practical methods like pausing to breathe before responding can help men avoid knee-jerk, defensive reactions and foster healthier communication and connection.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you can just start to interrupt the pattern of reacting immediately from an emotion, you can create a new pathway of being able to take some breaths so that you can...get some awareness of what is happening inside of me.&quot;</p>
<h2>Emotional Numbness Signals Overload, Not Emptiness</h2>
Numbing out emotionally is often a sign of emotional overload, not emotional vacancy. Instead of ignoring or shutting down feelings, view numbness as a prompt to investigate and carefully process what you’re carrying beneath the surface.
<p>&gt; &quot;Numbness is not a sign of emotional vacancy for the majority of men. Numbness is a sign of emotional fullness that you are over capacity.&quot;</p>
<h2>True Self-Esteem Comes From Facing Hard Truths</h2>
Developing real self-worth is tied directly to confronting difficult personal challenges rather than avoiding them. Men who work through their emotional burdens and take action on what they know is hard build lasting self-esteem and congruence in their lives.
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s a very simple truth and equation around developing worth which is confronting and doing hard things that you know are hard that you know you need to do.&quot;</p>
<h2>Redefining Masculinity: Embrace Both Competence and Depth</h2>
Modern masculinity is best realized when men develop not just competence and drive, but also emotional depth, empathy, and a balanced life beyond achievement. Embrace a broader skill set, including reflection and vulnerability, for deeper fulfillment and stronger relationships.
<p>&gt; &quot;We&apos;ve overindexed on like one specific thing. And that hasn&apos;t been the truth for men throughout human history...It&apos;s always been a part of of our development as men.&quot;</p>
<h2>Emotional Containment: Holding Space Without Suppression</h2>
Emotional strength is not about suppressing your feelings, but containing and processing them so they don’t control your reactions. Mastering your emotional charge allows you to provide emotional safety for others, lead effectively, and respond intentionally in tough situations.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s becoming a a man who is capable of dealing with the intensity and the charge within himself so that he can learn to deal with the intensity and the charge of others.&quot;</p>
<h2>Breaking the Cycle: Share Needs and Desires Openly in Relationships</h2>
Avoid built-up resentment and emotional distance by consistently expressing your actual needs, wants, and boundaries in intimate partnerships. Bringing your full, authentic self—including desires and vulnerability—prevents idealization, bitterness, and loss of intimacy.
<p>&gt; &quot;You have to confront, here&apos;s the need that I have. Here&apos;s the want that I have. Here&apos;s the expectation or the desire that I have that I&apos;ve been just chronically withholding from the relationship. and then to start to slowly bring that forward...&quot;</p>
<h2>Socially Accepted Coping Mechanisms Can Be Addictive</h2>
Not all addictions are obvious. Being perpetually busy, workaholic, overusing “productivity” or even seeking constant achievement can serve as unhealthy escapes from dealing with emotions. Challenge yourself occasionally to do nothing and observe any discomfort that arises as valuable information.
<p>&gt; &quot;I think just being busy, just being like the chronically busy person...that&apos;s part of our culture, right? It&apos;s very socially acceptable. It doesn&apos;t look like an addiction, but I think that many of us are addicted to being busy.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] If You Want Financial Freedom In 2026, Do This | Alex Smereczniak]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QDN8EZHQ2Y4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-19</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 23:00:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QDN8EZHQ2Y4">If You Want Financial Freedom In 2026, Do This | Alex Smereczniak</a></h1>
<h2>Franchising as an Overlooked Path to Wealth</h2>
<p>Franchising is widely misunderstood and undervalued as a path to financial freedom in America, offering accessible routes to significant wealth—even for those without millions in startup capital or a novel business idea. Exploring thousands of franchises, not just household food brands, can reveal hidden opportunities for entrepreneurial success.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There are more millionaires generated from franchising than all combined players ever in the NFL... there are a lot of hidden gems of brands and industries that are really taking off.&quot;</p>
<h2>Entry Points Range from Affordable to Premium</h2>
<p>You don&apos;t need to be rich to get started; many franchises require significantly less capital than commonly assumed, and financing options like SBA loans can help you launch. Research and select a franchise that fits your means and interests, considering both low-cost and upscale opportunities.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Of those 4,000 brands, there&apos;s some as affordable as $10,000 to get into...SBA will borrow you up to $5 million across multiple loans... typically depending on the brand you&apos;re getting into, you need 50k, I&apos;d say, liquid and over 150k net worth.&quot;</p>
<h2>Optimal Franchise Selection Means Finding the Right Fit</h2>
<p>Choosing a franchise should feel like tailoring a business to your strengths and interests. Look for systems offering strong operational support, brand value, and long-term growth rather than simply chasing trends.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;If you&apos;re going to do franchising you need to think about this over a 10-year period... in five years, what value is this brand going to be providing me that justifies this ongoing 6% royalty?&quot;</p>
<h2>Home Services and “Unsexy” Niches Offer Major Upside</h2>
<p>While food franchises get the spotlight, steady wealth often comes from sectors like home services, senior care, or turf installation. These require less up-front investment, can produce high margins, and are less subject to consumer trends.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Home services does phenomenally well... for 100 to 150k grand, you can own a business that on average is generating $1.3 million in annual revenue with profits around $270,000 a year.&quot;</p>
<h2>Scaling Up: Systems and Delegation Enable Passive Income</h2>
<p>Once you master the basics, expanding to multiple units and hiring layers of managers can turn an active business into a source of significant, relatively passive cash flow. Develop operating playbooks and delegate as you scale.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;He&apos;s got this... system and line of defense where each brand has a basically a COO over it... once that system is in place there&apos;s so much redundancy... you get to five of those, you know, generate 750K in relatively passive income.&quot;</p>
<h2>Do Rigorous Due Diligence and Avoid Broker Pitfalls</h2>
<p>Be skeptical of franchise brokers: many only show a select list of brands and are motivated by sky-high commissions. Always independently validate franchise performance, scrutinize disclosure documents, and speak with existing franchisees to hear the real story.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s no lensure to become a franchise broker... what does that attract? A lot of people who are going to say what they need to say to get a huge payday... I tell people to go look at the item 20 [of the disclosure]... And then the best validation is just go talk to other franchises, people who are actually doing it, who are in it.&quot;</p>
<h2>Practical Economics: Understand Cash Flow, Not Just Hype</h2>
<p>Focus on the true economics: assess build-out costs, margins, and realistic returns. Most strong franchises should provide 20-25% or higher cash-on-cash returns, but always verify with actual numbers and be wary of brands that evade clear answers.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;A franchisee is upset if they&apos;re not north of 25% IRR... that&apos;s not factoring in the enterprise value when you go to sell. And franchises trade at 1 to 2x more of EBITDA than an independent business because it&apos;s derisked...&quot;</p>
<h2>The Value of Following Proven Playbooks</h2>
<p>You don’t need a groundbreaking idea to win—executing well on a proven model, cultivating reliable management, and growing steadily can produce exceptional wealth and freedom.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I just followed the playbook. I am good at finding real estate and making deals with the landlords and I started with one and now I got 50 and I make 20 million a year...&quot;</p>
<h2>Hard Work and Operator Mentality Remain Crucial</h2>
<p>Success in franchising, as elsewhere, isn’t effortless. It still demands discipline, attention to detail, and a willingness to get your hands dirty—even in “passive” or systematized businesses.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There is no shortcut. It is all going to be hard work... Most people can go figure this out. It&apos;s not going to be this cakewalk... If you got the work ethic and you&apos;re willing to do it, franchising is a great way that&apos;s derisked.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] Watch this before 2026, and thank me later]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DcNRcQkjgm8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-20</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 23:00:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DcNRcQkjgm8">Watch this before 2026, and thank me later</a></h1>
<h2>Start with "Getting Light": Clear Clutter to Build Momentum  </h2>
Begin planning your year by removing physical and digital clutter from your environment—delete unused apps, cancel unnecessary subscriptions, clean your car and workspace. This small, tangible action creates instant momentum and marks a fresh start, making big annual planning feel less overwhelming.
<p>&gt; &quot;Getting light means getting rid of all the apps on your phone that you don&apos;t use. Getting rid of canceling all the subscriptions that you don&apos;t use that you&apos;re paying, you know, stuff. Going to your closet and donating all the clothing that you don&apos;t wear... It&apos;s a sign of newness. It&apos;s a sign of like I&apos;m coming into the year getting rid of stuff that I don&apos;t need anymore.&quot;</p>
<h2>Annual Review: Audit and Celebrate Your Year  </h2>
Review your calendar month by month, collecting highlights big and small onto one sheet of paper. Relive the meaningful moments and learn from both successes and gaps, making your achievements tangible and ready for the next year’s planning.
<p>&gt; &quot;I like to go through my phone and I&apos;ll write down all the highlights. My calendar is my highlight reel... Maybe it&apos;s my kid&apos;s football game or maybe it was a concert I went to and just make sure that I have a full recap of the year so I can look at it on one piece of paper.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Photobooks and Handwritten Letters to Mark Your Progress  </h2>
Create a year-end photo album of your memories, and send handwritten thank you notes to people important to your journey. These tangible tokens make accomplishments real and relationships stronger, reinforcing gratitude and connection.
<p>&gt; &quot;A great year-end strategy is to make a year-end family or yearend review book... One thing that I love to do is I write handwritten letters. I love to spend a little bit of time and write thank you letters to people that like, hey, you know what? There&apos;s eight billion people in the world. You chose me to be on your podcast.&quot;</p>
<h2>Be the "CEO" of Your Life by Planning Work Around Life  </h2>
Design your calendar to prioritize personal fulfillment over reacting to external demands. Place your most meaningful activities first, treating your life as your most important project—your calendar becomes your blueprint, not just a record of obligations.
<p>&gt; “I feel like in general, most people plan their life around work. And I think it&apos;s really important to plan work around your life... I want to have my blueprints that I want to follow.”</p>
<h2>The Calendar is Your Most Honest Autobiography  </h2>
Your calendar reflects what you actually prioritize. Use it intentionally to allocate energy to what matters most, giving yourself permission to say no to distractions and yes to what lights you up.
<p>&gt; &quot;The calendar is your most honest autobiography. It is your highlight reel. At least for me, it&apos;s where I want to put my energy towards and when I have things on my calendar, it helps me. It gives me permission to say no because if it&apos;s on my calendar, that means I have energy for it.&quot;</p>
<h2>One Year, One Major Goal: Set a "Misogi"  </h2>
Choose one big, challenging, year-defining goal (your "Misogi") that energizes and stretches you. Make it visible on your calendar as the defining event of your year—something you will be proud to remember decades later.
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s an old Japanese ritual called the misogi... you do one big year defining thing every year... And if you can do that, how old are you?... you&apos;d have 50 monumental things that you&apos;ve accomplished in your life. That&apos;s a heck of a ride, right?&quot;</p>
<h2>Model the Right Blueprint—Don’t Just Chase Others’ Successes  </h2>
Pick role models who align with all your values, not just professional achievement. Seek examples of people thriving in work, health, family, and adventure, and model your life blueprint accordingly for holistic success.
<p>&gt; &quot;So, they got success in their career, but they also have success at home and they&apos;re healthy... For me, winning is winning in all those areas. Having my cake and eating it too with my friends and family with a big ass, you know, fork.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>