<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Stefano YT RSS]]></title>
    <link>https://st-costa.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://st-costa.github.io/YT_highlight_feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Feed di highlights dei video YouTube]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:01:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] The Dark Subcultures of Online Politics - Joshua Citarella]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qNCHDE1vgS8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 23:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qNCHDE1vgS8">The Dark Subcultures of Online Politics - Joshua Citarella</a></h1>
<h2>The Meme-Driven Evolution of Political Subcultures  </h2>
The guest explains how online meme culture among teenagers has predicted and shaped wider political trends, moving from niche internet subcultures to mainstream influence. The transformation of fringe ideas into mass movements reflects the scaling power of digital media.
<p>&gt; &quot;We now see those same narratives and in some cases literally the same memes posted to audiences in the hundreds of thousands or millions. So the scale on these things, we call it early detection. How do you find something that is going to get big in the future? It&apos;s like political trend casting.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Rise of Right-Wing Populism and Shifting Party Coalitions  </h2>
There’s been a dramatic and unexpected global shift toward right-wing populism, even among groups that historically aligned with labor interests—surprising both political analysts and the left.
<p>&gt; &quot;The thing that has come out of it to the great surprise of people on the left is not like a renewed trade unionism... but it is this new international nationalism. We don&apos;t yet know what to call it but generally the rise of right-wing populism as a push back to austerity anti-immigration politics this kind of stuff.&quot;</p>
<h2>Gen Z’s Unique Political Context: Information Overload and Lack of Consensus  </h2>
Unlike past generations, Gen Z grew up with boundless information access and no clear political consensus, fostering experimentation with countless ideologies and accelerating radicalization pipelines.
<p>&gt; &quot;Growing up in Gen Z, you don&apos;t have that 1989 liberal democracy consensus... Instead, you are born into a world that has no political answers for you while you&apos;re given the complete archive of the internet to tr trudge through every possible meme and political text that&apos;s ever written...&quot;</p>
<h2>Irony, [__]posting, and the Problem of Earnest Belief  </h2>
Much of online radicalization and meme culture blurs the line between irony and sincerity, with users sometimes adopting extreme views they originally forwarded only as jokes, a process dubbed "irony poisoning.”
<p>&gt; &quot;Irony poisoning is when you float something that is a joke and then you say this is not what I really believe but I&apos;m posting it to like piss off the libs or something like that and then a few years later you kind of like work your way up to it and you&apos;re like actually yeah this is what I believe.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Pipeline Metaphor: Fluid Political Identities and Media Narratives  </h2>
The concept of radicalization as a “pipeline” is both useful and misleading, as media often exaggerates its implications, while in reality, people’s political identities and coalitions are constantly shifting.
<p>&gt; &quot;The great irony of like the pipeline metaphor to me was that belief systems are in motion. I think actually all belief systems are in motion. ...when they talk about very popular podcasts being a pipeline to extremist politics... I think that that is a gross gross mischaracterization.&quot;</p>
<h2>Online Communities as Real-World Political Actors  </h2>
Fringe digital groups can emerge as active political forces, influencing everything from street activism to electoral campaigns—sometimes outpacing traditional parties in grassroots mobilization.
<p>&gt; &quot;During the Georgia Senate runoff, he [Destiny] mobilized his Twitch followers and had more people canvasing and knocking doors than the Capital D Democratic Party... the call to action from a media entity is larger than a proper political party.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Left’s Struggle with Masculinity and Losing Young Men  </h2>
The guest examines how contemporary left-wing movements, especially in academic and activist spaces, have alienated young men, leading them towards other political alternatives—even when some seek to participate constructively.
<p>&gt; &quot;I would hear just... endless kind of casual misandry and these people&apos;s political needs are not important and it&apos;s their turn to take a back seat. It&apos;s like this is really going to bubble over. This is this is not good. ...they would just be met with like this kind of vicious activist rhetoric that was meant to basically scare them off...&quot;</p>
<h2>Horseshoe Theory and the Unpredictable Alliances of Modern Politics  </h2>
Anti-establishment sentiments now drive people to unexpected combinations of right and left views, with new voting patterns emerging that blur traditional ideological boundaries.
<p>&gt; &quot;So there is a noninssignificant portion of the population that voted for Trump in 2024 and Mumani in 2025... those people exist. So they&apos;re they&apos;re open they&apos;re open to a lot of ideas.&quot;</p>
<h2>Performance Activism, Effectiveness, and Generational Disconnect  </h2>
Public stunts by climate activists and others often fail to persuade the broader public, as effective movement-building requires appealing to practical interests and building broad, inclusive coalitions.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you join some political organization, and all they can tell you is like, &apos;Well, no airplanes, no hamburgers, we&apos;re going to take stuff away from people.&apos; ...That doesn&apos;t work anymore. And so they voluntarily just exit those types of movements.&quot;</p>
<h2>Personal Hardship, Resilience, and Shaping Worldview  </h2>
The host and guest connect their own health challenges to greater empathy and understanding of societal vulnerability, with hardship sometimes fostering deeper resilience and more nuanced politics.
<p>&gt; &quot;It&apos;s so front and center of your experience that if you are dealing with something, especially something that affects your energy or your cognition or your mood, like it&apos;s the window through which you experience the world. It&apos;s like looking at the world through a dirty window.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] How to Build Systems (So Your Business Runs Without You)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEK5CZy17Ng</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-2</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:42:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEK5CZy17Ng">How to Build Systems (So Your Business Runs Without You)</a></h1>
<h2>Escaping the Bottleneck: Make Yourself Less Essential</h2>
<p>The more your business depends on you, the harder it becomes to grow or exit. To build a valuable, scalable company, deliberately remove yourself from daily operations and shift key responsibilities to others, aiming to work on the business rather than in it.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;The more valuable you are, the less valuable the company is.&quot;</p>
<h2>From Doer to Owner: Move to the Owner’s Box</h2>
<p>Entrepreneurs must choose between being the all-star player or truly owning their business. Decide to let go of control, transition to leadership roles, and cultivate a team and systems that operate independently, freeing you for big-picture strategy and rest.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Do you want to be down on the court hitting the last minute...jump shot, or do you want to be up in the owner’s box?&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Default Constraints to Force Real Change</h2>
<p>Establish hard boundaries for your time—like set working hours—to force prioritization and empower your team. Default constraints quickly reveal what’s essential and help break old habits, creating space to actually step out of the weeds.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I&apos;m going to leave at 5:30 every day...and what do you know? Magically I got my work done in that block of time because I did.&quot;</p>
<h2>Map Your Business Processes for Clarity and Delegation</h2>
<p>Visually map every core process (e.g., how you get customers, serve them, and create products) with tools like whiteboards and sticky notes. This makes workflow bottlenecks obvious and enables delegation of responsibilities.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Every business does three things. You make stuff, you sell stuff, and you fulfill stuff...create a visual map of how that happens.&quot;</p>
<h2>Identify and Focus on the Biggest Constraint</h2>
<p>Stop adding new ideas and instead consistently identify the single largest constraint blocking growth—whether it’s demand (more leads) or supply (capacity to handle leads)—and focus resources on solving only that next hurdle.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What is my right next thing? What is the thing that I&apos;m going to do next? Every problem in business is going to come down to one of two things. Is it a supply constraint or a demand constraint?&quot;</p>
<h2>Hire Functional Leaders, Not Helpers or Clones</h2>
<p>Don’t just hire assistants or try to clone yourself. To scale, deliberately seek skilled functional leaders—heads of sales, marketing, product—who can own entire business areas without your micromanagement.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What you need to typically do is realize that that constraint is solved by a functional leader...hiring a functional leader and building a team of those...&quot;</p>
<h2>Assign Clear Accountability and Metrics for Each Step</h2>
<p>For every step in your mapped processes, assign direct ownership and transparent success metrics. This enables team members to be true drivers (not just helpers) and clarifies both individual and team accountability.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Every single sticky note, every single box is going to have corresponding what we would call critical accountability bullets...this is how we create our scorecards.&quot;</p>
<h2>Only Systemize What Matters Most</h2>
<p>Systematize only the crucial parts of your operation, not everything. Focus documentation, measurement, and optimization on your most important “value engines.” Ignore or eliminate orphaned activities that don’t meaningfully drive results.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;One of the biggest mistakes that companies make when they&apos;re trying to systemize is they try to document everything. Don&apos;t do that. Just document the ones that are really, really, really important.&quot;</p>
<h2>Build a Company Top Talent Wants to Join</h2>
<p>If you want to attract great talent, develop systems and a culture where they can succeed without heroic individual efforts. Systems attract rockstars because they see they can make an impact—and these systems allow you to succeed even without “A-players.&quot;</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;My goal is to build a company that doesn&apos;t require them because I know that&apos;s the kind of company that rockstars and a players want to come and work for.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[HBR] Future of Business: Mars CEO on How Business Can Be a Force for Good]]></title>
      <link>https://hbr.org/podcast/2025/12/future-of-business-mars-ceo-on-how-business-can-be-a-force-for-good</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:47:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[HBR] <a href="https://hbr.org/podcast/2025/12/future-of-business-mars-ceo-on-how-business-can-be-a-force-for-good">Future of Business: Mars CEO on How Business Can Be a Force for Good</a></h1>
<h2>Long-Term Vision Enables Sustainable Growth  </h2>
Building a strategy for sustainability requires a balance between delivering short-term performance and long-term value, made possible by a long-term ownership mindset. Prioritize decisions that set up your company for success across decades, not just quarters.
<p>&gt; &quot;We’d like to think we think in generations and not just in quarters. And because of our ownership, we carry the name of our owners on the door, we have an obligation to make sure that we behave well in society.&quot;</p>
<h2>Tie Incentives to Non-Financial Goals  </h2>
Integrate sustainability metrics into compensation to drive accountability at all management levels. By making social and environmental impact part of leaders' measurable objectives, you embed purpose into daily business.
<p>&gt; &quot;40% of my compensation is on non-financial metrics... I would say to a public listed CEO, &apos;How do you feel about having 40% of your compensation on greenhouse gases?&apos;&quot;</p>
<h2>Engage Supply Chain Partners for Real Impact  </h2>
Most environmental impact may occur outside your company in the supply chain. Build deep relationships with suppliers and invest in tools (like satellite imaging) and systems to ensure responsible sourcing and drive change with farmers and producers.
<p>&gt; &quot;About 85% of our environmental footprint sits outside the company, so what is called Scope 3... and that is working with predominantly farmers across the world.&quot;</p>
<h2>Make Sustainability a Core Business Process  </h2>
Incorporate sustainability reviews and investment decisions directly into regular business planning. Treat environmental impact assessments and investments as integral as financial planning.
<p>&gt; &quot;We have tried to integrate sustainability in the way we do business... when we review the plan... we are reviewing the investment levels in sustainability in our food business, our pet food business, our snacking business, and in our veterinary business.&quot;</p>
<h2>Invest in Innovation that Balances Purpose and Profit  </h2>
Embrace the challenge of aligning purpose with profit by reframing sustainability as an opportunity for innovation and growth, rather than a trade-off.
<p>&gt; &quot;Purpose and profit are not enemies, that it is our task that we have to do both... a lot of that has come from products where we have done work on sustainability.&quot;</p>
<h2>Align Product Changes to Tangible Customer Benefits  </h2>
When communicating sustainability efforts, focus on clear, product-specific changes that directly improve environmental outcomes. Consumers respond best to transparent, concrete claims.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you advertise a positive environmental impact of a product close to the product, i.e. you explain the exact thing you have changed on a product, then that brand will benefit... recyclable packaging, consumers absolutely understand.&quot;</p>
<h2>Building Resilient Supply Chains  </h2>
Localize production where possible and diversify sources to weather geopolitical and climate-related disruptions. Resilience is crucial for stability and continuing to serve customers in an unpredictable world.
<p>&gt; &quot;The most important thing is resiliency, to build up a supply chain that is resilient enough to take some of these hits that are coming with political issues across the globe.&quot;</p>
<h2>Foster Empathy and Self-Awareness in Leadership  </h2>
Cultivate empathetic, self-aware leaders who listen and build a respectful, inclusive workplace. Recognize that societal issues increasingly enter the business sphere, and leaders must navigate them with openness and care.
<p>&gt; &quot;The most important thing as leader is to have empathy and listen... Self-awareness is more important today than what it was in the past because the softer values of leadership are much more in focus.&quot;</p>
<h2>Capital Allocation Based on Clear, Goal-Linked Methodology  </h2>
Allocate capital towards both financial and sustainability goals, recognizing that not every investment will have the same financial ROI, but some are essential for social responsibility and long-term value.
<p>&gt; &quot;We have an allocated number in sustainability that is linked to our goal. So we want to reduce by X percent at that date and we work what are the investments required to achieve that goal... not all of our investments have the same requirements.&quot;</p>
<h2>Over-Invest in Continuous Personal Learning  </h2>
Stay innovative by fostering personal curiosity and lifelong learning, both for yourself and your teams. Encouraging ongoing development is essential for remaining adaptive and inventive in a changing world.
<p>&gt; &quot;If you go back and study what really constitutes the most important elements of leadership, the most important is personal learning. It has the biggest correlation. And the way you learn, you need high curiosity.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] Improve Energy & Longevity by Optimizing Mitochondria | Dr. Martin Picard]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMkQUlBtFlk</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-4</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:01:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMkQUlBtFlk">Improve Energy &amp; Longevity by Optimizing Mitochondria | Dr. Martin Picard</a></h1>
<h2>Aging and Hair Graying Are Not Fixed—You Can Reverse It by Managing Stress</h2>
<p>Science now shows that graying hair is not always a permanent, irreversible sign of aging. Stress can accelerate graying, and reducing stress can actually reverse it, at least temporarily. If you notice your hair going gray, take it as a sign to examine stress in your life and find manageable ways to reduce or cope with it—like improving sleep, meditating, or creating a restorative routine.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;What we discovered is that hair graying, at least temporarily, is reversible. This was surprising because it goes against this notion that aging is a linear... process that just happens over time no matter what you do.&quot;</p>
<h2>Energy Is About Flow, Not Just Intake—Focus on Transformation, Not Calories</h2>
<p>Energy in the body isn’t just about eating more; it’s about how well your mitochondria transform and distribute that energy. Overeating or eating poorly doesn’t give you more energy—it can actually make you more sluggish. Instead, focus on behaviors that boost your mitochondria’s ability to transform energy, such as regular exercise, quality sleep, and stress reduction.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Just consuming more energy didn&apos;t give you more energy... the issue is not lack of energy going into the system. It&apos;s that the transformation of energy that occurs in mitochondria somehow is not happening correctly.&quot;</p>
<h2>Tailor Your Habits to Enhance Mitochondrial Health (And Thus, Your Vitality)</h2>
<p>To boost your energy and aging trajectory, go beyond simply exercising and eating well. Quality sleep, meditation, and aligning activities with your sense of purpose and enjoyment all support healthier, more efficient mitochondria. Regular movement, being “out of breath” each day, and occasional hunger (like skipping breakfast sometimes) can also optimize mitochondrial function.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There are critical things that you can do in terms of how you eat, your mindset, and exercise that can offset those changes. His lab also famously showed that graying of hair is indeed related to stress and is also fortunately reversible.&quot;</p>
<h2>Too Much or Too Little Resistance Is Harmful—Strike a Balance in Life and Training</h2>
<p>Growth, learning, and physical improvement require the right amount of resistance or challenge. When resistance is too high, it’s overwhelming and can break you; too little, and the body and mind atrophy. In both exercise and life, consciously select activities and problems that push you enough to foster adaptation, but not so much that you’re crushed.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;The art of education is finding the right amount of resistance to expose a child to. If the problem is too hard... you crush them. If you don&apos;t apply any resistance there&apos;s no rules then the energy is like this and then they&apos;ll never learn. There needs to be just the sweet spot.&quot;</p>
<h2>Purpose and Positive Social Connections Directly Improve Brain Energy</h2>
<p>Doing things that inspire you and building real connections with others tangibly improve mitochondrial function in your brain. Focus on meaning and relationships as intentionally as you do diet and exercise, since psychological fulfillment helps prevent depression and bolsters mental and physical resilience.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;People who felt more purpose in life and who felt more connected to others... seemed like was sufficient to increase the energy transformation capacity of the mitochondria in their brain.&quot;</p>
<h2>Sleep and Meditation Conserve and Restore Energy—Prioritize Them Actively</h2>
<p>You can’t “out-eat” or “out-supplement” poor sleep. Sleep and deep relaxation free up energy for repair, healing, and growth. Incorporate restful pre-sleep routines, naps, or even daily meditation, as these deliberately reduce the energy “cost” of stress and allow your mitochondria to recharge, leading to better overall performance and mental clarity.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Meditating it seems and in some trained people can bring energy expenditure down by 40%. This is more than sleep.&quot;</p>
<h2>Being Mindful of Inflammation Saves Energy for What Matters</h2>
<p>Inflammation, whether from illness, overeating, or chronic stress, drains your energy and reduces what’s available for living, thinking, moving, and feeling good. Prioritize anti-inflammatory habits like regular activity, occasional fasting, and especially managing stress—to keep inflammation and its energetic “tax” low.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Inflammation is an energetic signal. If there are cytoines in your blood, somewhere in your body... the major cytoines that we think about... it&apos;s recruiting the fat. It recruits the liver. And it sends signal to the brain... you need to recover.&quot;</p>
<h2>There Is No One-Size-Fits-All Diet—Experiment to Find Your Best Pattern</h2>
<p>Scientific studies on diets often average out huge individual differences. Tune into your body’s response—try different eating patterns, such as intermittent fasting or low-carb, and stick with what&apos;s energizing and sustainable for you. Safe self-experimentation can reveal what genuinely boosts your vitality and mitochondrial health.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s no one diet that is a best diet for everyone. I&apos;ve seen people thrive on very different diets... Safe self-experimentation is the only solution.&quot;</p>
<h2>Avoid Excessive Use of Stimulants and Energy “Borrowing” Substances</h2>
<p>Stimulants like amphetamines, cocaine, or even excessive caffeine can temporarily mask fatigue, but they “borrow” energy from the future and can cause long-term damage to your energy system. Use them sparingly, if at all, and be mindful of how you truly feel—opt for natural energy-building strategies first.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;You&apos;re borrowing energy from the future is what you&apos;re doing. And it&apos;s not just the crash that happens later. It&apos;s the long-term effects of this.&quot;</p>
<h2>Build Daily Energy with Small, Consistent Habits</h2>
<p>Simple tweaks such as skipping breakfast occasionally (“being hungry once in a while”), ensuring at least some daily physical activity that elevates your breath and pulse, and practicing mindfulness or meditation can all meaningfully improve how your body makes, transforms, and allocates energy—improving both healthspan and lifespan.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;Trying to be hungry once in a while is probably a good thing. And then being out of breath... that&apos;s probably good for you. I need to say something about meditation. I think somehow meditation does something to our energy that is valuable.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Chris Williamson] Why Comedies Suck Now - Judd Apatow (4K)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9p0NbOWWsgI</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:01:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Chris Williamson] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9p0NbOWWsgI">Why Comedies Suck Now - Judd Apatow (4K)</a></h1>
<h2>Channeling Pain and Discomfort into Creativity</h2>
<p>Harness personal challenges and discomfort as fuel for creative or professional pursuits. Use difficult experiences to develop new perspectives and heightened observation skills—the sensitivity gained from hardship often becomes a catalyst for success and originality across fields like comedy, music, and business.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;discomfort and pain seems to be a real creative catalyst...it just makes you more sensitive and I think you just pay attention in a different way to the world and you don&apos;t feel safe.&quot;</p>
<h2>Practicing in Public and Embracing Creative Failure</h2>
<p>Accept that developing performance or public skills often requires learning in front of others and embracing failure as a necessary step. Treat “bombing” or public mistakes as valuable R&amp;D, not something to hide from, and use the information to improve as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;the only profession that you have to learn how to do it in front of people...I&apos;m bombing but I&apos;m in it. This is it. We&apos;re doing it. So I got kind of excited even after a bomb that I was entering the business.&quot;</p>
<h2>Separating Creation from Critique to Boost Output</h2>
<p>When working on something creative, separate the “flow” or generation phase from the evaluation or critique phase. Write, perform, or brainstorm freely first, then return in a different mindset to judge what’s valuable. This method builds momentum and diminishes destructive overthinking.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I try to separate the the flow moment from the judgment moment and I think that people slow down because they&apos;re trying to do it at the same time.&quot;</p>
<h2>Find Value in Mentorship and Trusted Feedback</h2>
<p>Actively seek mentors who genuinely understand your work and can provide honest, constructive advice. Surround yourself with collaborators who aren’t afraid to challenge or correct you, and recognize that their perspective can fuel growth and confidence.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;he let me write the Grammys for him and then he hired me...just that he liked it put so much gas in my tank...him being gone I think has really hurt me because it really was one of the things I leaned on.&quot;</p>
<h2>Collaboration and “Being a Good Hang” Matter</h2>
<p>Professional success in creative fields is not just about talent—it’s about being enjoyable and reliable to work with. Foster strong collaborative environments and avoid being a “room killer,” as your attitude can impact both opportunities and long-term relationships.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;if you&apos;re not cool and they&apos;re on the bubble about whether or not to do it, they&apos;re always not going to do it if they don&apos;t want to have that relationship... part of it is like do people want you around.&quot;</p>
<h2>The Public Nature of Progress: Status and Comparison</h2>
<p>Regular comparison to peers and public performance can drive insecurities but also motivate improvement. Recognize that careers often require enduring periods where others seem to succeed faster, but focusing on personal growth and unique paths can lead to long-term fulfillment.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I would get depressed...trying to figure out, you know, what am I going to do here? Because I was young...I wasn&apos;t groundbreaking...But it took a long time for me to find myself almost till you know freaks and geeks where I realized oh the more personal I am the better it is...&quot;</p>
<h2>The Cycle and Value of Originality in Comedy (and Other Creative Work)</h2>
<p>Understand that trends in creative industries are cyclical, and true innovation often comes from outsiders with fewer resources who take risks. Don’t wait for gatekeepers&apos; approval—sometimes pioneering work means starting small, permissionlessly, and proving value over time.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;we have the technology we just need some lunatics to make something groundbreaking now cheap because that&apos;s what changes the genre is that someone just did...&quot;</p>
<h2>Navigating Feedback: Taking Criticism and Saying “No”</h2>
<p>Learn to create a culture where honest, sometimes uncomfortable feedback is welcomed. Value those who can critique you constructively—even in high-stakes scenarios, this openness improves the quality of your work. Be prepared to defend your vision when it matters most, but remain open to changing it when given good reason.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;you invite all your friends and friends of friends who are writers and then you have to tell them, &apos;Okay, hit me with the truth.&apos; There&apos;s nothing you can say that will offend me...create a space where people will say what they feel. And it&apos;s always helpful.&quot;</p>
<h2>Overdelivering and Working for Free Early in Careers</h2>
<p>At the start of your career, don’t be afraid to offer your work for free or go beyond expectations to break in and build relationships. Consistently overdeliver so you become indispensable, opening doors to paid opportunities and skill development.</p>
<p>&gt; &quot;I just wanted to overd deliver it to a ridiculous extreme. So if Shan wanted a few jokes for the Grammys, I&apos;d write him a hundred...no one is going to outwork him. And maybe when I wasn&apos;t as good, but it mattered because I cared so much.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[My First Million] The 2025 Milly Awards]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xGL-H9vQI-8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-6</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[My First Million] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xGL-H9vQI-8">The 2025 Milly Awards</a></h1>
<h2>Redefining Investment: Prioritize Life Upgrades, Not Just Finance</h2>
Don’t limit “investment” to just stocks and bonds—consider moves that make your life happier and richer. Prioritizing emotional and personal returns, like proximity to loved ones or simplifying your lifestyle, can have a profound impact on daily wellbeing. Consider downsizing, moving closer to friends or family, or offloading possessions to increase happiness.
<p>&gt; “Owning less stuff, moving to the city, being near your family, working in person in an office. That&apos;s actually a pretty big change overall. Huge change. It&apos;s definitely made me a lot happier.”</p>
<h2>Embrace Specific and Public Financial Bets with Long-Term Intentions</h2>
Making lump-sum investments based on conviction, and holding for the long term—and even sharing your decisions publicly—can clarify your thinking and boost returns. Commit to assets you believe in for at least a decade, rather than chasing trends.
<p>&gt; “...what companies or assets do I want to own for like a 10 year period? 10 years is my sort of default hold period. And that&apos;s what I&apos;ve been doing since then.”</p>
<h2>Seek Out High Agency Decisions and Take Action on Conviction</h2>
Recognize when unique opportunities align with your expertise or intuition, and act quickly. Many missed opportunities come from hesitation or not responding to outreach for partnerships or investments, even when you have an advantage.
<p>&gt; “I passed on three different, $10 billion startup investments that were right in my wheelhouse...all I needed to do was answer.”</p>
<h2>Pursue a “Misogi”: A Big, Year-Defining Personal Challenge</h2>
Designate one demanding goal or challenge—physical, creative, or emotional—each year to create lasting memories and personal growth. Pick a challenge that feels surreal or intimidating, put it on the calendar, and document your progress.
<p>&gt; “One of his core concept is this concept of a Misogi…a hard year defining thing. So you&apos;ll always remember, oh, that was the year I hiked...that was the year I did my first Ironman...you&apos;ll always remember.”</p>
<h2>Use Money Deliberately to Build Community and Happiness</h2>
Instead of only using money to upgrade your lifestyle, use it to enhance community and social connection—such as by living close to friends or creating intentional shared spaces. This leads to greater well-being than simply buying more or bigger things.
<p>&gt; “The people you have around you, your close-knit community is the number one thing that will improve your happiness. So we did that...built their own little micro community.”</p>
<h2>Frame-Breaking Hospitality and the Power of Radical Excellence</h2>
Strive for not just good, but “unreasonable” excellence in any pursuit—whether it’s business or personal—by over-delivering and weaving delight into small details. High intentionality and caring execution can set you apart dramatically.
<p>&gt; “We are going to go above and beyond and we are going to be excellent...pursuing excellence for the sake of just trying to be great at a couple things.”</p>
<h2>Delete Social Apps to Reclaim Time for Deep Work and Reading</h2>
If distraction and shallow content are draining your focus, delete social media apps or set up strict boundaries. Free up hours for rich, high-quality inputs, like reading books, and notice the improvement in clarity and depth of thought.
<p>&gt; “I took my phone and I just deleted X, deleted Twitter, deleted YouTube, deleted Reddit...I&apos;m just going to not consume any social this year.”</p>
<h2>Reset Your Morning Routine for Maximum Impact</h2>
Start your day with early, consistent workouts to set a productive tone and improve focus. Finish your workout by 7 a.m., and go to bed at 10 p.m. to sustain the habit.
<p>&gt; “My workout is finished at 7 a.m. I&apos;m done by 7 a.m...the secret is you have to go to bed at 10.”</p>
<h2>Running: Accessible High-Return Habit for Body and Mind</h2>
Running is a habit nearly anyone can adopt, with measurable progress and emotional benefits. Start at a pace that feels comfortable—even if it’s slow—and build up gradually. Stick with it to see life-changing improvements in health and mindset.
<p>&gt; “I think anyone can get to the point where they&apos;re running marathons, running three miles a day. That&apos;s how I started....You will get to a point where your body, you know, becomes more efficient. And over time, you&apos;re going to be running 10 minute miles at that walking feeling pace and you&apos;re going to love running.”</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Andrew Huberman] How to Set & Achieve Goals | Huberman Lab Essentials]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYuw-8pwnp8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">highlight-7</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:01:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Andrew Huberman] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zYuw-8pwnp8">How to Set &amp; Achieve Goals | Huberman Lab Essentials</a></h1>
<h2>Set Moderately Challenging, Concrete Goals  </h2>
The most effective goals are those that are challenging yet achievable; they should feel slightly out of reach, but not impossible or too easy. To maintain motivation and activate your physiological systems, aim for goals that stretch your current abilities.
<p>&gt; &quot;So it turns out that when goals were moderate, when they were just outside of one&apos;s immediate abilities or that one felt that yeah, that would take a lot of effort but it&apos;s within range or maybe in range like maybe I can do it, maybe I can&apos;t, then there was a near doubling of the likelihood that they would engage in the ongoing pursuit of that particular goal.&quot;</p>
<h2>Focus Visual Attention on a Distant Point to Boost Motivation  </h2>
Before starting a task or whenever you need to take action toward a goal, pick a specific point outside your immediate reach (on a wall, or in the distance) and hold your gaze there for 30–60 seconds. This primes your body and brain for action by recruiting your attention, increasing alertness, and raising blood pressure.
<p>&gt; &quot;You&apos;re going to focus your visual attention on one point beyond your perpersonal space...and with some effort, you&apos;re going to hold your visual attention for 30 to 60 seconds...Again, it places your brain and body into a state of readiness. And then the idea is to move into the particular actions that bring you closer to your goal.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Foreshadowing Failure to Sustain Effort  </h2>
Instead of constantly visualizing success, routinely imagine the negative consequences of failing to reach your goal. Specifically thinking about what could go wrong or how you’ll feel if you fail helps keep you driven and focused.
<p>&gt; &quot;There&apos;s a near doubling in the probability of reaching one&apos;s goal if you focus routinely on foreshadowing failure, you think about the ways in which things could fail...the more specific you can get by writing down or thinking about or talking about how bad it will be if you don&apos;t achieve your goals, the more likely you are to achieve those goals.&quot;</p>
<h2>Break Down Goals Into Milestones and Assess Weekly  </h2>
To leverage your brain’s dopamine system, set concrete milestones between now and your ultimate goal, and review your progress at regular intervals, like once a week. This approach keeps motivation high and helps correct your course as you go.
<p>&gt; &quot;I think that checking in at the end of a week, looking back on the previous week, and assessing how well you performed in pursuit of a given goal or how many times you did something that you wanted to do or avoided something that you didn&apos;t want to do...is a reasonable and tractable schedule to assess once a week.&quot;</p>
<h2>Practice Space-Time Bridging for Flexible Focus  </h2>
Use the “space-time bridging” practice to train shifting your attention from your internal state to increasingly distant visual targets and back, using cycles of three slow breaths at each focal point (internal sensation, your body, a mid-distance point, a distant horizon, and wide panoramic view, then return). This exercise helps you flexibly align your focus with immediate tasks or long-term goals.
<p>&gt; &quot;What you first do is you would close your eyes and you would focus as much of your attention including your visual attention on your inner landscape...Then you would open your eyes and you would focus your visual attention on some area on the surface of your body...then...to outside my body to some location in the room...then further away...then return immediately to my internal landscape...The entire thing takes about 90 seconds to 3 minutes depending on how many breaths you do.&quot;</p>
<h2>Understand and Harness Dopamine as Motivation  </h2>
Dopamine is not just for pleasure, but is the key chemical for motivation and effort toward goals. Even a small reward or an unexpected win spikes dopamine and renews drive, while failing to reach an expected outcome causes a drop and disappointment—knowing this, set up your milestones and little wins to keep momentum.
<p>&gt; &quot;Dopamine is the common currency by which we assess our progress toward particular things of particular value...Dopamine really sits at the heart of our motivational state to seek out goals and to seek pleasure...The biggest increases in dopamine are response to things that are positive and unexpected.&quot;</p>
<h2>Use Behavioral Tools to Train Motivation and Focus  </h2>
Prioritize behavioral strategies like visual focusing and shifting attention before relying on supplements or chemicals to boost motivation, because building these habits actually makes your attention and drive systems stronger over time through neuroplasticity.
<p>&gt; &quot;Behavioral tools used over time engage neuroplasticity. As we start to practice using our visual system to harness our attention...we get better and better at using those systems. In fact, the systems for focus and motivation themselves have plasticity.&quot;</p>
<h2>Plan Concrete Actions Toward Your Goal  </h2>
List specific steps you will take to reach your goal instead of relying on vague intentions. Concrete action plans enhance your likelihood of consistent progress and allow for clear weekly self-assessment and milestone setting.
<p>&gt; &quot;Second, plan concretely. You need a concrete set of actions that you&apos;re going to follow in order to reach your goals.&quot;</p>]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>