<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Stefano YT RSS]]></title>
    <link>https://st-costa.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://st-costa.github.io/YT_highlight_feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Feed di highlights dei video YouTube]]></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] How Private Equity Makes Money]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XML9l6_qf_Y</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XML9l6_qf_Y</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XML9l6_qf_Y">How Private Equity Makes Money</a></h1>
<h2>Investors Seek Proprietary Deal Flow in Niche Markets</h2>
Top banks and investors are interested in unique opportunities where deals are exclusive and not widely shopped around. They especially value access to companies in specialized or captive markets that others can't easily reach.
<h2>Acquisition.com Targets the Under-Served $1–100 Million Range</h2>
Acquisition.com focuses on businesses earning between $1 million and $100 million annually, a market segment largely overlooked by both small-scale coaches and large consulting firms. This segment is identified as a prime area for generating outsized investment returns.
<h2>Multiplier Effect of Growing Profit in Mid-Sized Businesses</h2>
By making key improvements, a business with modest profits (like $3 million in EBITDA) can increase its value significantly as profits grow. For example, boosting EBITDA from $3 million to $8 million can result in a potential sale price jumping from around $12 million to as much as $100 million, making this growth stage very lucrative.
<h2>Bridging the Gap to Institutional Investors</h2>
Once a business reaches about $5 million to $10 million in profit, it becomes an attractive target for large, institutional investors looking to deploy significant amounts of capital. Acquisition.com’s strategy is to acquire companies just before this threshold, make the necessary changes, and realize substantial gains when selling to these larger buyers.
<h2>Free 10-Stage Business Growth Roadmap</h2>
The speaker offers a detailed, free roadmap outlining the ten stages companies go through from zero to over $100 million in revenue. This guide covers eight core business functions, typical challenges at each stage, and the steps needed to progress, drawing on successful experiences across various industries. The roadmap is available at acquisition.com/roadmap.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Breaking Italy] Live del venerdì, commentiamo gli avvenimenti della settimana!]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVk_x-NtHqE</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVk_x-NtHqE</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Breaking Italy] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVk_x-NtHqE">Live del venerdì, commentiamo gli avvenimenti della settimana!</a></h1>
<h2>Caos tecnico e dettagli personali all’inizio della live</h2>
La live inizia con alcuni minuti di ritardo dovuti a problemi tecnici e disordine sotto la scrivania, che l’autore descrive come fonte di stress. Vengono condivise considerazioni ironiche sulla vita da influencer e piccoli dettagli personali, creando un’atmosfera informale e coinvolgente con i moderatori e il pubblico.
<h2>Uso delle armi da parte della polizia in Italia</h2>
Viene affrontato il tema delle dotazioni e dei limiti nell’uso delle armi da fuoco dalla polizia italiana rispetto ad altri paesi. In Italia, gli agenti spesso non portano la pistola durante manifestazioni rischiose per evitare che venga sottratta e perché l’approccio è mediamente più restrittivo rispetto ad altri paesi come gli Stati Uniti. Si sottolinea l’importanza di questa prudenza e il rischio di normalizzare l’impiego delle armi in operazioni di ordine pubblico.
<h2>Confusione e complottismi sul rilascio degli “Epstein Files”</h2>
Si discute il rilascio caotico dei documenti legati al caso Epstein, criticando la gestione che ha alimentato confusione e teorie complottiste a causa della mancata censura dei nomi delle vittime e del caos informativo. Si sottolinea la difficoltà di distinguere tra fatti, ipotesi plausibili e complotti, ribadendo la necessità di trattare queste notizie con cautela, responsabilità e senza speculazioni.[br][br]
<h2>Caso Corona e limiti del giornalismo-scandalo</h2>
Viene commentato il caso di Fabrizio Corona, criticando il modo in cui gestisce le presunte denunce e la diffusione di informazioni sensibili per lo più a scopo di scandalo e monetizzazione, piuttosto che per una reale volontà di informare. Si riflette sul rischio che la spettacolarizzazione prevalga sul giornalismo serio, evidenziando il ruolo delle grandi aziende (come Mediaset) nella risposta ai contenuti controversi.
<h2>Fiducia e limiti nella resilienza europea</h2>
Si esprime fiducia nella capacità dell’Unione Europea di superare periodi di crisi rispetto a un mondo che vede altre potenze sempre più distanti da valori condivisi. Viene ribadita l’importanza del progetto europeo anche di fronte a deriva sovranista, criticità sul riarmo, gestione dei migranti e crisi energetica, sottolineando che il venir meno di tale coesione porterebbe a maggiore caos e instabilità globale.
<h2>Transizione energetica ed energia nucleare</h2>
Il tema della dipendenza energetica europea, specie dalla Russia, viene riletto alla luce degli errori strategici del passato, come il mancato investimento sul nucleare e l’affidamento eccessivo su combustibili fossili. Si sostiene apertamente la necessità di puntare sul nucleare per garantire autonomia energetica e ridurre l’impatto ambientale, invitando a superare le paure culturali legate alle scorie.
<h2>Cambiamento del lavoro con l’intelligenza artificiale</h2>
Viene affrontato l’impatto dell’IA sul settore del software e di altri lavori creativi, sottolineando che i cambiamenti tecnologici sono inevitabili e che i lavoratori dovranno adattarsi e reinventarsi. Si esclude l’idea che l’Unione Europea possa semplicemente “proteggere” chi perde il lavoro, come spesso non è successo per precedenti transizioni, rilevando che i più colpiti saranno coloro che svolgevano mansioni più semplici e ripetitive.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Alex Hormozi] Why Ambitious People Stay Mediocre]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A248pGXTSoY</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A248pGXTSoY</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Alex Hormozi] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A248pGXTSoY">Why Ambitious People Stay Mediocre</a></h1>
<h2>Rejecting Industry Standards and Embracing Higher Expectations</h2>
<p>A core theme is to challenge the concept of “industry standards,” which only set you up to be average. Ashi argues that aiming for the average means you’ll achieve typical, uninspiring outcomes since most businesses are mediocre or struggling. Instead of benchmarking against the norm, you should set and hold much higher standards for yourself and your business, becoming the true “standard setter” rather than accepting what everyone else tolerates.</p>
<h2>Relentless Pursuit and Multiple Angles to Solve Problems</h2>
<p>Success comes from attacking problems from many different angles, not just trying the same thing repeatedly and giving up when it fails. Ashi emphasizes that leaders and teams should be resourceful and persistent, exploring every possible solution and pushing boundaries instead of stopping at the first sign of difficulty. The number of creative “attack vectors” applied to a problem is often the real indication of your standards and commitment.</p>
<h2>Profit, Distinctiveness, and the Need to Hold the Line</h2>
<p>“Profit is unnatural” because the world, people, and systems naturally push toward mediocrity and equilibrium. Ashi shares advice from a billionaire mentor, emphasizing that it takes discipline and effort to maintain profitability and uniqueness—continuously resisting the downward pull towards being normal and holding the line on what standards are acceptable.</p>
<h2>Physical Laws, Not Conventional Wisdom, Should Guide Ambition</h2>
<p>To achieve exceptional outcomes, Ashi suggests working backward from what’s physically possible—relying on the laws of physics and math—rather than listening to conventional wisdom, industry excuses, or naysayers who claim something can’t be done. If a goal does not violate the laws of nature, then it is potentially achievable, no matter how unreasonable it seems.</p>
<h2>The Value and Cost of Being Unreasonable</h2>
<p>Being “unreasonable” and stubborn about your standards is key to achieving extraordinary results. Ashi points out that world-class entrepreneurs don’t require consensus or external validation; they push for outcomes others would call impossible. It takes energy, dedication, and sometimes conflict to maintain higher standards, but the outsized returns go to those willing to bear that cost.</p>
<h2>Distinctiveness Requires Continuous Effort</h2>
<p>Drawing from Jeff Bezos and Richard Dawkins, Ashi reinforces that staying distinct in business or in life is like biological survival—it requires continual work to resist the powerful pull toward typicality and mediocrity. Distinctiveness fades without ongoing effort, and so maintaining high standards and originality is a lifelong, active process rather than a one-time achievement.</p>
<h2>Never Apologize for Big Goals</h2>
<p>Unrealistic goals should not be a source of embarrassment or apology. Ashi’s experience breaking a world record for book sales illustrates the principle: set unreasonable ambitions, attack them with determination, and prepare for skeptics. If you strive greatly, even if you miss, you achieve far more than you would by aiming for something “reasonable.”</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] The Real Reason I Moved to Las Vegas]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nwE_l7JlEYo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nwE_l7JlEYo</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nwE_l7JlEYo">The Real Reason I Moved to Las Vegas</a></h1>
<h2>Why the Move from Texas to Vegas</h2>
The speaker explains that they left Austin, Texas, mainly due to the intense political climate and challenging weather. After trying out various cities, they decided on Las Vegas because they enjoyed its environment more and found the weather preferable to the humidity and heat in Texas and other places.
<h2>Approach to Politics and Business</h2>
They state that they avoid discussing politics publicly and only get involved when political decisions impact business, especially regarding taxes and policies that affect entrepreneurs. Their focus is on capitalism and business growth, favoring strategies that create financial advantages.
<h2>Entrepreneurship and Risk-Taking Mindset</h2>
The conversation touches on the idea that entrepreneurs are natural risk-takers, likening their approach to gambling. However, instead of casinos, they prefer to make big investments in their business where they feel they have the advantage, sometimes spending millions before a product even launches.
<h2>Finding the Right Place to Live</h2>
The speaker and their partner spent a year traveling between cities like Denver and Salt Lake City before choosing Vegas. They enjoyed the flexibility of moving freely until a place felt right, ultimately settling in Vegas and making a spontaneous decision to stay for the long term.
<h2>Avoiding the Vegas Gambling Trap</h2>
While acknowledging Vegas’s reputation for gambling, the speaker explains that they don’t get caught up in it because they channel their appetite for risk into entrepreneurship and investments, preferring ventures where the odds are in their favor.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] How Intuition Actually Works]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5JgZJaaGJs</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5JgZJaaGJs</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5JgZJaaGJs">How Intuition Actually Works</a></h1>
<h2>Intuition Is Based on Pattern Recognition  </h2>
Intuition isn't a magical sense but rather the result of your brain subconsciously picking up on patterns and variables from past experiences, even if you can't immediately identify what they are.
<h2>Trusting Intuition as a Signal, Not a Superpower  </h2>
While intuition deserves attention during decision-making, it shouldn't be treated as a mystical ability. Instead, it often points to something real that you haven't consciously pinpointed yet and may become clearer with further reflection.
<h2>Free 10-Stage Business Roadmap Resource  </h2>
A detailed 10-stage roadmap for growing from zero to over $100 million in business, broken down by business functions and growth constraints, is available for free. The roadmap is based on practical experience across various types of companies and can be accessed through a provided link.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Breaking Italy] Fabrizio Corona oscurato dai social: è censura?]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ab8tgVO08LM</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ab8tgVO08LM</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Breaking Italy] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ab8tgVO08LM">Fabrizio Corona oscurato dai social: è censura?</a></h1>
<h2>Il caporalato nei servizi di delivery e il caso Glovo</h2>
Il video analizza come il caporalato, spesso associato all'agricoltura, sia diventato centrale anche nel settore dei rider urbani. Viene raccontato il recente controllo giudiziario imposto alla società Fudinho, che gestisce Glovo in Italia, con accuse di sfruttamento di migliaia di rider. Le indagini evidenziano paghe molto inferiori agli standard legali, orari di lavoro estenuanti, e pratiche che maschererebbero rapporti di lavoro subordinato dietro false partite IVA, sfruttando le zone grigie della legge.
<h2>Le reali possibilità di cambiamento per i rider sfruttati</h2>
Pur con i provvedimenti giudiziari come quello imposto a Glovo, il contesto strutturale di sfruttamento difficilmente cambierà a breve. Il video sottolinea che il caporalato è sostenuto da incentivi economici enormi e da una domanda costante di manodopera a basso costo, specie tra persone vulnerabili, come molti immigrati. La soluzione va oltre il singolo intervento giudiziario e richiede cambiamenti politici, sociali e culturali.
<h2>Fabrizio Corona, le accuse a Signorini e la rimozione dei suoi contenuti</h2>
Viene approfondito il caso del canale YouTube di Fabrizio Corona, che ha diffuso accuse di ricatti sessuali a Alfonso Signorini, mostrando presunte chat e documenti. Le modalità, tra cui la monetizzazione delle testimonianze e l'esposizione pubblica di nomi senza tutele, hanno aperto due indagini: una su Corona (per revenge porn e diffamazione) e una su Signorini (per presunta violenza sessuale ed estorsione).
<h2>La questione della censura: tra tribunali, piattaforme e aziende private</h2>
Il video chiarisce che la rimozione dei contenuti di Corona da YouTube e social non equivale a una censura in senso stretto, ma riflette l’azione di aziende private come Mediaset, Google e Meta che tutelano i propri interessi e rischi legali. Corona, nonostante i ban dai social, continua a trovare visibilità tramite altri canali, dimostrando i limiti del concetto di censura sulle piattaforme digitali.
<h2>Etica, responsabilità e limiti del diritto di cronaca online</h2>
Il conduttore riflette sulla sottile linea tra diritto di cronaca e rispetto per la dignità delle persone coinvolte nei casi mediatici. Le pratiche di Corona, che monetizza contenuti sensibili e viola la privacy senza essere soggetto ai vincoli deontologici giornalistici, mostrano come tali comportamenti sfuggano spesso al controllo e all’etica senza produrre benefici reali per la società.
<h2>Differenze nel trattamento giudiziario e dalle piattaforme in base al potere dei soggetti coinvolti</h2>
Viene evidenziato come la rapidità delle decisioni giudiziarie e delle piattaforme sia influenzata dal peso delle parti in causa: una segnalazione da Mediaset produce effetti molto più forti e immediati rispetto a quella di piccole realtà o privati, ribadendo una realtà asimmetrica nella gestione delle controversie online.
<h2>Aggiornamenti su politica internazionale e processi ai social network</h2>
In chiusura, vengono citate notizie di rilievo: la crisi di governo nel Regno Unito a causa dei file Epsteam, le trattative nucleari tra Iran e Stati Uniti, e il primo processo statale negli USA contro Meta per non aver protetto i minori dallo sfruttamento sessuale online, indicando come questi temi saranno centrali nel prossimo periodo.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] I Have a Challenge for You...]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=da00CukmxWI</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=da00CukmxWI</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=da00CukmxWI">I Have a Challenge for You...</a></h1>
<h2>The 10x Input Challenge  </h2>
Identify the specific input-output equation that defines how you get closer to your goal, whether it's in business, fitness, or any field. Once defined, push yourself to do ten times the input you think is necessary, rather than making small incremental increases. Most people seriously underestimate the level of action required and see doubling efforts as enough, when they actually need to think in terms of 10x or even 100x their efforts to see transformative results.
<h2>Unlocking Leverage in Entrepreneurship  </h2>
Moving forward in business requires gaining leverage, which comes from relinquishing control and systematizing tasks. Instead of personally handling all core activities like sales, marketing, and admin, you start delegating and building systems so that others can do the work and you can multiply your results. This progression—from doing everything oneself, to recruiting help, to building layers of leverage—is essential for substantial growth.
<h2>Unlearning the Need for Control  </h2>
A critical stage in entrepreneurship is letting go of the compulsion to control every aspect of your business. The very traits that drive people to start businesses—the desire for independence, control, and personal involvement—must be unlearned for further growth. The path from self-employment to true business ownership is a continuous process of giving up roles and trusting systems and other people.
<h2>The Business Exists for the Customer, Not You  </h2>
It’s common for entrepreneurs to create businesses to fulfill personal needs, but ultimately, the business should exist to serve its customers. Your personal fulfillment is not the primary purpose of the company, and real business growth happens when the organization can thrive without its founder’s ongoing involvement.
<h2>Free Resource: Zero to $100M Roadmap  </h2>
As a practical tool for growth, the speaker offers a comprehensive, free 10-stage business roadmap detailing what it takes to scale from zero to over $100 million in revenue. The guide covers growing headcount, resolving constraints, and navigating each function of a company, with actionable steps based on real experience in multiple industries.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Vinh Giang] Why People Don’t Take You Seriously (Until You Speak Like THIS!)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MZAHghIDtX8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MZAHghIDtX8</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Vinh Giang] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MZAHghIDtX8">Why People Don’t Take You Seriously (Until You Speak Like THIS!)</a></h1>
<h2>Record and Review for Better Communication</h2>
<p>The “record and review” process helps speakers identify subtle communication habits—such as filler words, distracted gestures, or vocal delivery—that may weaken their authority or presence. By reviewing both audio and visual elements separately, individuals can see what works well and what can be improved, leading to significant and immediate upgrades in how they are perceived.</p>
<h2>Self-Awareness and Continuous Improvement</h2>
<p>No matter how skilled someone is, there is always room to refine communication by paying close attention to energy, expression, and habits. Developing self-awareness through reviewing one’s own performance makes even accomplished speakers aware of areas for further growth, like sharpening responses or balancing stillness and movement.</p>
<h2>Isolating Audio and Visual Cues</h2>
<p>By listening to only the audio or watching the video without sound, communicators can focus on specific details, such as filler words, tone, hand movements, or facial expressions. This helps them analyze and adjust elements like unnecessary introductory phrases, overactive gestures, or distracting patterns that may not be obvious in the heat of the moment.</p>
<h2>Advanced Tips for Impactful Speaking</h2>
<p>Experienced communicators can level up by trimming initial pleasantries from their answers and diving straight into the core message, making their responses punchier and more authoritative. Balancing expressive movement with intentional stillness adds gravitas and highlights key points, especially in emotionally weighted conversations.</p>
<h2>Connecting With the Audience</h2>
<p>Using bridging phrases and inviting listeners to see themselves in the story strengthens audience connection. Varying vocal tone, including pauses, and asking relatable questions helps the audience feel more involved and engaged throughout the conversation.</p>
<h2>Practicing Different Delivery Styles</h2>
<p>Practicing both energetic, playful delivery and calmer, more controlled responses allows speakers to adapt their style to match the mood or weight of the question. Mastering this flexibility helps them convey vulnerability, depth, and authenticity, enhancing their overall impact.</p>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Breaking Italy] I deputati di Vannacci (eh, già) sono contrari alle armi all’Ucraina]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=68tOhf6SU34</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=68tOhf6SU34</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Breaking Italy] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=68tOhf6SU34">I deputati di Vannacci (eh, già) sono contrari alle armi all’Ucraina</a></h1>
<h2>La trasformazione dell'Ucraina: da paese in difficoltà a esportatore di droni militari</h2>
L'Ucraina, inizialmente vista solo come vittima e dipendente dagli aiuti occidentali durante la guerra con la Russia, sta ribaltando la narrazione grazie a una straordinaria crescita dell'industria bellica, in particolare nella produzione di droni da combattimento. Con circa 450 aziende manifatturiere di tecnologia militare, ora mira non solo all'autosufficienza ma anche a esportare armi e droni innovativi verso l'Europa, dimostrando resilienza e capacità di adattamento anche in condizioni estreme.
<h2>Nuove misure di Israele in Cisgiordania e le reazioni internazionali</h2>
Il gabinetto di Netanyahu ha approvato nuove leggi che facilitano l'acquisto di terre da parte dei coloni israeliani in Cisgiordania, abolendo vincoli storici e rendendo pubblico il registro fondiario. Queste normative riducono drasticamente il potere dell'autorità palestinese e spalancano le porte a nuovi insediamenti, in violazione degli accordi di Oslo e del diritto internazionale. La comunità internazionale ha espresso forti condanne, ma senza prospettive di azioni concrete per fermare queste politiche espansionistiche.
<h2>Situazione in Gaza: violenze e tensioni senza tregua</h2>
Nonostante l'avvio di una presunta seconda fase del piano di pace e l'apertura del valico di Rafah, gli attacchi militari israeliani su Gaza continuano e il numero dei civili palestinesi uccisi cresce costantemente anche dopo il cessate il fuoco. I trasferimenti di persone sono minimi rispetto alle aspettative e resta il sospetto che Israele mantenga volontariamente l'alta tensione per giustificare il proprio approccio duro nella Striscia.
<h2>Europa e migrazione: nuove restrizioni e paesi terzi sicuri</h2>
Il Parlamento Europeo ha approvato nuove regole sull'immigrazione che consentono il trasferimento dei richiedenti asilo verso paesi extra-UE ritenuti "sicuri", anche in assenza di legami diretti con questi stati. È stata stilata una lista di nazioni sicure, tra cui molte con criticità sui diritti umani, e i migranti da questi paesi affronteranno procedure accelerate e maggiori difficoltà a ottenere asilo.
<h2>Proteste e corruzione politica in Albania</h2>
In Albania migliaia di manifestanti sono scesi in piazza a Tirana contro il governo di Edi Rama, chiedendo le dimissioni della vicepremier coinvolta in scandali di corruzione. Le proteste sono degenerate in scontri con la polizia, mentre la corruzione rimane uno dei principali ostacoli per l'ingresso del paese nell'Unione Europea entro il 2027.
<h2>Sparatoria in Canada: uno degli episodi più gravi nel paese</h2>
Nel distretto di Tumblor Ridge, nella British Columbia, una sparatoria in una scuola ha causato nove morti e più di venticinque feriti. L'autrice, trovata morta per suicidio, rimane senza movente certo. L'evento è uno dei più gravi nella storia recente del Canada e ha suscitato vaste discussioni pubbliche.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] "I Own an E-Com Brand but Make Zero Profit. Should I Sell It?"]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xsyFueNR8Qg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xsyFueNR8Qg</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xsyFueNR8Qg">&quot;I Own an E-Com Brand but Make Zero Profit. Should I Sell It?&quot;</a></h1>
<h2>Shifting from E-Commerce Brand to 3PL Success</h2>
The speaker describes building a wellness e-commerce brand that achieved $5–10 million in annual revenue, but struggled with low profitability and mounting debt. In contrast, helping to scale a family-run 3PL (third-party logistics) business has proven far more profitable and sustainable, leading to a natural shift in focus to the 3PL.
<h2>The Limitations of Non-Branded E-Commerce</h2>
The conversation highlights that in e-commerce, true value lies in building a recognizable brand. The wellness business relied heavily on media arbitrage and product ads, without developing a strong brand identity or partnerships, making it unsellable and less attractive for acquisition compared to a true brand.
<h2>Accepting When to Move On</h2>
There is discussion around the difficulty and guilt of closing down the e-commerce business. The advice given is clear: don’t waste time trying to revive a low-profit venture just for a potential acquisition. Instead, it’s better to accept the lessons learned and focus energy on the more promising 3PL opportunity.
<h2>Importance of Formalizing Equity in New Ventures</h2>
One key recommendation is to clearly define and document ownership and equity arrangements in the new, successful 3PL business. This ensures that the value created is protected and incentives are aligned as the business grows.
<h2>Leveraging Learned Skills and Talent</h2>
The speaker is encouraged to recognize the marketing and sales skills acquired through growing the e-commerce business, as well as the value in bringing talented team members over to the 3PL. Transferring these assets can accelerate the success of the new venture.
<h2>When to Scale and When to Hold Back</h2>
In the context of rapid 3PL growth, the advice is to be strategic about pulling new monetization levers. There’s no need to rush into additional profit models unless they are at risk of disappearing soon. Focus first on fixing operational bottlenecks before scaling further.
<h2>Balancing Operations and Sales Leadership</h2>
With operational constraints emerging due to fast growth at the 3PL, the speaker is advised to temporarily focus on ops—either by stepping in personally or hiring experienced help—while planning to return to sales and expansion as soon as possible to maximize company momentum.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Breaking Italy] Gli Epstein Files saranno uno degli scandali più gravi della nostra era]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AKTZFNIPraA</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AKTZFNIPraA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Breaking Italy] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AKTZFNIPraA">Gli Epstein Files saranno uno degli scandali più gravi della nostra era</a></h1>
<h2>Sovraccarico informativo e caos nei file Epstein</h2>
La pubblicazione massiccia degli Epstein files (oltre 3 milioni di pagine e migliaia di immagini e video), richiesta da mesi al Congresso USA, ha creato un’enorme confusione. La quantità di dati, la presenza di informazioni incomplete, manipolazioni tramite AI e la tendenza dei social a diffondere teorie non verificate rendono quasi impossibile distinguere tra verità e speculazione. Inoltre, molte informazioni sensibili sulle presunte vittime sono rimaste visibili, mentre i nomi dei possibili colpevoli sono stati censurati, alimentando sospetti di manipolazione politica e coperture.
<h2>I nomi più coinvolti: Trump, Clinton, Gates e gli altri</h2>
Nei file spiccano i nomi di Donald Trump, Bill Clinton e Bill Gates, spesso associati a Epstein prima dello “spartiacque” del 2008, anno della sua prima condanna. Mentre Trump è menzionato 40.000 volte, non emergono prove dirette di coinvolgimento, ma diverse segnalazioni e rapporti lo accostano ad accuse molto gravi. Clinton viene collegato a strette relazioni con Ghislaine Maxwell e la Clinton Global Initiative, mentre emergono aneddoti non verificati su Gates. Anche altre figure di spicco, come Steve Bannon, Elon Musk e Peter Thiel, compaiono in corrispondenze che mostrano il tentativo di Epstein di influenzare elite politiche e tecnologiche.
<h2>Il ruolo ambiguo delle censure e delle indagini mancate</h2>
Numerosi documenti sono stati oscurati o censurati, specialmente in relazione ai nomi dei presunti colpevoli, alimentando accuse di protezione politica da parte del Dipartimento di Giustizia ora considerato vicino a Trump. Nonostante il Congresso abbia ora accesso a versioni meno censurate, la mancanza di trasparenza e l’assenza di reali indagini suggeriscono che difficilmente emergeranno conseguenze concrete per le personalità coinvolte.
<h2>Difficoltà nel distinguere realtà da illazioni</h2>
Il materiale divulgato mostra conversazioni e riferimenti che non costituiscono prove definitive, ma alimentano costantemente teorie e illazioni, anche attraverso manipolazioni sui social. La mole dei dati e l'assenza di volontà investigativa portano a uno scenario dove la verità resta frammentaria e spesso inquinata da speculazioni, mentre la pressione pubblica e mediatica sembra destinata a proseguire senza reali risposte.
<h2>Le connessioni internazionali di Epstein</h2>
Dai file emerge l’ampiezza della rete di Epstein, tra tentativi di agganciare potere in Russia (senza prove di incontri con Putin, ma numerosi contatti politici) e rapporti ravvicinati con personaggi israeliani, come Ehud Barak. Ci sono sospetti e dicerie circa un suo coinvolgimento come “asset” di servizi segreti come il Mossad, ma nessuna evidenza solida: nei fatti, Epstein appare più come un abile manipolatore indipendente che cerca influenza tra le elite globali.
<h2>Conseguenze politiche fuori dagli Stati Uniti</h2>
Se negli USA la pubblicazione degli Epstein files non ha provocato reazioni istituzionali di rilievo, in altri paesi sono emerse dimissioni e scandali, come nel caso britannico che ha coinvolto figure di spicco del Labour Party, portando a dimissioni dalla Camera dei Lord e dall’entourage del premier. Questo evidenzia come la portata dello scandalo e delle connessioni di Epstein sia davvero globale, anche se spesso le conseguenze reali restano limitate.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] "Does Pricing Affect Churn?"]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jtDzaRZTT5w</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jtDzaRZTT5w</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jtDzaRZTT5w">&quot;Does Pricing Affect Churn?&quot;</a></h1>
<h2>Churn and Price Are Not Directly Linked</h2>
While it's often assumed that higher-priced communities have higher churn, the correlation isn't straightforward. Churn is more dependent on matching the price to the real value delivered and ensuring the right prospects are qualified, rather than price alone.
<h2>Price Drops Do Not Always Reduce Churn Profitably</h2>
Lowering your community's price typically reduces churn if all else stays equal, but this doesn’t guarantee higher profits. A significant price cut that only minimally reduces churn can actually be a poor decision financially.
<h2>LTV and Earnings Per Click Matter Most</h2>
Ultimately, the focus should not be on minimizing churn at all costs, but on maximizing LTV (lifetime value) and earnings per click. Price, conversion rates, and customer retention all play a role, so decisions should optimize overall revenue, not just a single variable.
<h2>Price Optimization Is Less Impactful Than Expected</h2>
Experimentation shows that changes in pricing—like increasing from $6,000 to $9,000—often do not create dramatic differences in total revenue, due to offsetting effects on conversion rates and customer expectations. The impact of price is usually much less extreme than many anticipate.
<h2>Delivering Value and Targeting the Right Audience Is Key</h2>
The profitability of a community or offer depends most on delivering compelling value and aligning pricing with the needs and qualifications of your target prospects. Getting these fundamentals right is far more important than worrying about minor price adjustments.
<h2>Comprehensive Business Growth Roadmap Offered</h2>
The speaker shares a free resource: a 10-stage roadmap for scaling a business from zero to over $100 million, covering key business functions and common constraints. This roadmap is available via a link in the video description.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Breaking Italy] Live del venerdì, commentiamo gli avvenimenti della settimana!]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JbW_ZwXY1A0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JbW_ZwXY1A0</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Breaking Italy] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JbW_ZwXY1A0">Live del venerdì, commentiamo gli avvenimenti della settimana!</a></h1>
<h2>Interazione con la community e aggiornamenti personali</h2>
La live si apre con Shai che accoglie la community, risponde alle prime domande su progetti futuri e aggiorna sul suo stato personale e di salute. Spiega di aver dovuto mettere in pausa alcuni progetti, come il Night, a causa di problemi di salute, ma mostra ottimismo per il futuro se le cose andranno meglio.
<h2>Analisi della situazione politica italiana e della sinistra</h2>
Viene affrontato il tema dello stato attuale della politica in Italia, con particolare attenzione alla stabilità del governo Meloni, la difficoltà della sinistra a trovare una figura all’altezza e la percezione diffusa che solo Meloni sappia tenere il paese. Si riflette anche sul ruolo delle principali trasmissioni televisive politiche e sull’assenza di una vera rappresentanza progressista fuori da La7.
<h2>Europa, Draghi e gli Stati Uniti d’Europa</h2>
Si commentano le nuove dinamiche europee, sottolineando come anche i leader sovranisti abbiano iniziato a riconoscere il bisogno di maggiore integrazione. Draghi viene visto come figura centrale per un rilancio dell’unità europea, anche se la realtà degli “Stati Uniti d’Europa” viene giudicata ancora lontana e teorica.
<h2>Discussione sugli Epstein Files e la cultura dell’impunità</h2>
Viene criticata l’idea che i file su Epstein non abbiano rivelato nulla di nuovo, sottolineando invece la gravità dei contenuti emersi, il clima di impunità e la superficialità dei commenti online. Shai esprime frustrazione per il modo in cui certi temi vengono ingigantiti da teorie complottiste e per la mancanza di indagini su aspetti realmente inquietanti.
<h2>La comicità e la retorica del "non si può più dire niente"</h2>
Si esprime insoddisfazione per gli ultimi spettacoli di comici come Gervais e Chappelle, annoiati dalla retorica stanca sul “non si può più dire niente”. Viene evidenziata una stanchezza verso questa polemica e il desiderio di una comicità più innovativa e meno autoreferenziale.
<h2>Riflessioni sull'anonimato online e i suoi effetti positivi e negativi</h2>
Si discute il valore dell’anonimato su internet, riconoscendo sia i rischi legati all’abuso che i molteplici benefici, come protezione di fonti giornalistiche, tutela delle minoranze e libertà di espressione in contesti sensibili. Emergenze come i casi di cronaca dimostrano che la vera disumanizzazione spesso avviene anche senza anonimato.
<h2>Referendum e informazione: confusione e necessità di equilibrio</h2>
Ampio spazio è dedicato al dibattito sul referendum giustizia, denunciando un’informazione superficiale e polarizzata, con derive autoritarie brandite da entrambe le parti e poco spazio per l’analisi. Viene criticata la tendenza delle celebrità a influenzare il voto senza argomentazioni e si sottolinea la complessità della questione, auspicando maggiore chiarezza e approfondimento.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[How Money Works] How Epstein Won So Many Friends & Influenced So Many ̶p̶e̶d̶o̶s̶ People]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m192zxKJTBs</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m192zxKJTBs</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[How Money Works] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m192zxKJTBs">How Epstein Won So Many Friends &amp; Influenced So Many ̶p̶e̶d̶o̶s̶ People</a></h1>
<h2>Epstein’s Unusual Rise to Influence</h2>
Jeffrey Epstein was not born into wealth or power but managed to build relationships with some of the most influential people in the world, spanning politics, finance, academia, royalty, and entertainment. He leveraged early opportunities—such as a teaching position at a prestigious school and networking with wealthy parents—to ascend socially and professionally, demonstrating both persistence and a knack for using every connection to his advantage.
<h2>The Depth and Breadth of His Network</h2>
Epstein’s connections included a staggering range of individuals, from world leaders and billionaires to Hollywood executives and spiritual figures. These relationships often crossed typical social, political, and professional boundaries, illustrating how a small group of elite individuals repeatedly interact within a closed network that looks out for its own interests, regardless of broader societal divisions.
<h2>Building Power Through Relentless Networking</h2>
His ascent relied heavily on relentless and targeted networking. Epstein focused not only on those within the finance sector but also sought out people in academia, science, and the arts, connecting those who wanted prestige with those who had wealth. He attended high-profile events, cultivated introductions, and became known as the person who could make almost any connection happen, treating socializing as a core part of his work.
<h2>The “Elite Club” Mentality and Mutual Protection</h2>
The video highlights that the world’s ultra-wealthy and powerful operate within a small social sphere, attending the same global events and often siding with one another regardless of personal or political differences. This mutual protection means that public exposure of wrongdoing rarely leads to substantial consequences for insiders, helping explain the persistent sense of impunity.
<h2>The Role of Blackmail and Secrecy</h2>
While much about Epstein remains uncertain due to incomplete records, there is strong implication that part of his power came from gathering compromising information on peers, which he could use for blackmail. This secrecy—combined with the overlapping interests of those involved—both enabled his crimes and protected many participants from scrutiny.
<h2>The Limits of Incomplete Information and Why Context Matters</h2>
Because the full details of Epstein’s operations and connections remain secret or redacted, speculation and conspiracy theories thrive. The video stresses that without proper context, simply being named in the files can unfairly implicate individuals; many contacts were mundane, and guilt by association is not always justified. However, the lack of transparency leaves crucial questions unanswered and allows the network’s influence to persist.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] What Book Should I Write Next?]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OVVvonRkVds</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OVVvonRkVds</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OVVvonRkVds">What Book Should I Write Next?</a></h1>
<h2>Considering Topics for the Next Book</h2>
The speaker is deciding between a few different ideas for their next book, with audience feedback possibly influencing the choice by a small margin.
<h2>Book Idea 1: Profit and Pricing Strategies</h2>
One potential book would focus on practical tactics and hacks to increase profit within a business, emphasizing strategies around profit and pricing.
<h2>Book Idea 2: Writing a Sales Book</h2>
Another option is to finally write a sales book, despite feeling intimidated by the vast amount of knowledge and experience the speaker has about sales. This book would attempt to capture those insights in a structured format.
<h2>Book Idea 3: Operationalizing Personal Development Concepts</h2>
A third idea involves a book that operationalizes abstract personal development terms like trust, loyalty, integrity, guilt, shame, and trauma. Inspired by a previous discussion on mental toughness, this book would define and organize these concepts from a practical, actionable perspective.
<h2>Invitation for Audience Input</h2>
The speaker seeks audience feedback on which direction to take—focusing on pricing and profit, on sales, or on operationalizing personal development terms and traits.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Vinh Giang] 4 Levels of Speaking (Most Never Escape Level 2!)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QNsvsnkUOL0</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QNsvsnkUOL0</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Vinh Giang] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QNsvsnkUOL0">4 Levels of Speaking (Most Never Escape Level 2!)</a></h1>
<h2>Communication as the Foundation for Success  </h2>
Your ability to communicate effectively sets the ceiling for your success in your career, business, and relationships. Growth in every area depends on outgrowing your past patterns of communication.
<h2>The Four Levels of Speaking Progression  </h2>
There are four key stages to developing as a communicator: unaware (not recognizing issues), aware (noticing your weaknesses), skilled (deliberately practicing new behaviors), and mastery (communication becoming automatic). Progressing through these levels is essential to becoming a world-class communicator.
<h2>Three Key Areas of Communication  </h2>
Great communicators excel in three areas: vocal image (how you use your voice, including pitch, volume, and pace), visual image (body language, including gestures and facial expressions), and verbal image (the words you use, such as storytelling and clarity). Understanding and developing each area creates a powerful presence.
<h2>The Record and Review Process  </h2>
To improve, you must analyze your own communication through a process of recording yourself, then reviewing your performance in three ways: listening to your voice, watching with no sound for body language, and reading transcripts for verbal clarity. This breakdown reveals your specific strengths and weaknesses, allowing for tailored improvement.
<h2>Moving from Practice to Mastery  </h2>
Advancing from deliberate practice to mastery involves repeatedly cycling through three steps: trying one new behavior, reflecting on its effectiveness, and making small improvements. Over time, this mastery cycle makes effective communication second nature.
<h2>Embracing Discomfort Leads to Growth  </h2>
When adopting unfamiliar communication behaviors, it can feel awkward or fake—but reframing this discomfort as part of expanding your “instrument” is crucial. By pushing through the unfamiliar, you unlock your full communication potential.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] What It Takes to Be a Good Communicator]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=reuODMHvcvc</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=reuODMHvcvc</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=reuODMHvcvc">What It Takes to Be a Good Communicator</a></h1>
<h2>Closing 4,000 Sales and Communication Skills</h2>
The speaker has personally closed over 4,000 sales, mostly in person, and is considered an exceptional communicator. While sales experience contributed to communication skills, it was not the only factor; significant improvement also came from consistent practice.
<h2>The Role of Repetition and Feedback in Skill Building</h2>
Achieving proficiency in both sales and content creation required countless repetitions and direct feedback. Sales provided instant cues from buyers, while content creation offered rapid feedback on what resonated with the audience. Both arenas allowed the speaker to refine techniques quickly, though sometimes feedback can be misleading when success stems from factors outside one’s control.
<h2>Content Creation Journey and Growth</h2>
The speaker produced a massive volume of content—about 350 pieces per week—and spent years podcasting with little initial growth. Over four years, the podcast attracted only about 2,000 monthly listeners, but after actively seeking improvement and feedback, growth accelerated. Consistency alone was not enough without a focus on learning and adapting.
<h2>Offering a Free Business Growth Roadmap</h2>
At the end, the speaker offers viewers free access to a detailed, step-by-step roadmap for scaling a business from zero to over $100 million. It covers different stages of business growth, functional breakdowns, common challenges, and actionable steps, applicable across various business types. The resource is available for free via a provided link.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] The Story Behind the $100M Book Series]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ExRKuE_KFs</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ExRKuE_KFs</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ExRKuE_KFs">The Story Behind the $100M Book Series</a></h1>
<h2>Breaking a Guinness Record with Book Sales</h2>
The speaker achieved a Guinness World Record by selling 2.9 million books in 24 hours, an unprecedented feat for a non-fiction launch that was driven primarily by word of mouth and the practical value of the content.
<h2>The Origin and Structure of the Three-Book Series</h2>
Initially, the author wrote one massive book that was later divided into three focused volumes, each tackling a core part of the business process: offers, advertising, and monetization. These books were written simultaneously to capture his knowledge while it was still fresh.
<h2>Organic Growth and Word-of-Mouth Marketing</h2>
Despite starting with just 10,000 Instagram followers and no YouTube presence, the books gained traction through authentic word-of-mouth, as readers found real-world value and success, leading to exponential sales.
<h2>Demonstrating Concepts Through Meta Launches</h2>
Each book embodies the principles it teaches. The launch of the final book—focused on monetization—used the very monetization strategies outlined within it, serving as a live demonstration and culminating in a $100 million launch over 72 hours.
<h2>Free Value and Accessibility</h2>
The courses accompanying the books are offered for free, with revenue mainly from hardback sales. By providing valuable educational materials at no charge, the speaker prioritized impact over profit, further fueling the books’ popularity and success.
<h2>Frameworks for Creating Value and Making Offers</h2>
The first book distills “value” into actionable elements like speed, reduced risk, ease, and dream outcomes, teaching readers to craft offers that are irresistible. This step-by-step breakdown demystifies value creation and advertising methods for entrepreneurs at any level.
<h2>Real-World Impact on Readers’ Success</h2>
Readers regularly report significant business gains after applying the concepts from the books, with the author estimating that his frameworks have collectively helped people generate “a few billion” in revenue.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Breaking Italy] Gratteri e Nordio sul Referendum: stracci che volano e l’Italia a guardare]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93rIFdnBUWM</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93rIFdnBUWM</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Breaking Italy] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93rIFdnBUWM">Gratteri e Nordio sul Referendum: stracci che volano e l’Italia a guardare</a></h1>
<h2>Scontro politico e mediatico sul referendum sulla giustizia</h2>
Il referendum sulla riforma della giustizia, che si terrà il 22 e 23 marzo, sta alimentando forti polemiche tra figure di rilievo come Nicola Gratteri, Carlo Nordio e vari esponenti politici. Gratteri si schiera apertamente per il no, associando il sì a criminalità e poteri occulti, mentre Nordio, promotore della riforma e sostenitore del sì, definisce il CSM come influenzato da meccanismi “paramafiosi”, scatenando reazioni dure da magistrati e oppositori. Il clima è fortemente polarizzato e la questione, tecnicamente complessa, viene spesso banalizzata in slogan e schieramenti di personaggi pubblici.
<h2>Difficoltà di comprensione e disorientamento degli elettori sul referendum</h2>
La riforma oggetto del referendum è estremamente tecnica e perfino tra gli addetti ai lavori manca un accordo sulle sue ripercussioni, generando confusione generale tra i cittadini. L’informazione punta più sullo spettacolo e sulle discussioni tra personalità che su un reale approfondimento, rendendo normale sentirsi disorientati. Il conduttore invita a sentirsi liberi di ammettere dubbi e incertezze anziché farsi guidare solo dalle opinioni dei personaggi più noti.
<h2>Grave crisi energetica e sociale a Cuba aggravata dalle mosse di Trump</h2>
Cuba sta affrontando una delle sue peggiori crisi dagli anni Novanta, acuita dalle restrizioni statunitensi sulle forniture di petrolio, in particolare dopo l’arresto del venezuelano Maduro e i nuovi dazi imposti da Trump. La mancanza di carburante costringe il governo cubano a razionare le risorse, colpendo duramente trasporti, sanità e servizi pubblici, e portando a blackout, ospedali ridotti ai minimi servizi e paralisi del turismo, mentre milioni di cittadini stanno abbandonando il Paese.
<h2>Isolamento internazionale progressivo di Cuba e conseguenze</h2>
Sotto la crescente pressione degli Stati Uniti, molti Paesi storicamente vicini a Cuba stanno riducendo o sospendendo scambi e programmi, come il Venezuela per il petrolio e il Guatemala per i medici. Anche il turismo internazionale è crollato, con compagnie come Air Canada che sospendono i voli a causa della crisi. A differenza del passato, mancano “salvatori” esterni come il Venezuela post-URSS, lasciando il governo cubano in una posizione sempre più fragile e isolata.
<h2>Novità e reazioni sull’avvelenamento di Alexei Navalny</h2>
Cinque Paesi europei (Regno Unito, Francia, Germania, Svezia e Paesi Bassi) sostengono che l’oppositore russo Alexei Navalny sia stato avvelenato con una tossina rara, contraddicendo la versione ufficiale russa della morte naturale. Questa accusa alimenta pressioni internazionali su Mosca, con il Regno Unito che propone sanzioni aggiuntive; la vicenda rimane però ancora aperta e molto dibattuta.
<h2>Politica estera: Italia, Trump e conferenza sulla sicurezza di Monaco</h2>
Giorgia Meloni annuncia la partecipazione dell’Italia come osservatore al nuovo “Board of Peace” promosso da Trump, tra critiche interne sull’autonomia nazionale in politica estera. Alla conferenza di Monaco emerge la richiesta statunitense che l’Europa assuma più responsabilità nella propria sicurezza, mentre leader come il cancelliere tedesco Merz dichiarano finita l’epoca delle vecchie regole e avvertono la necessità di prepararsi a potenziali sacrifici.
<h2>Comunicazioni personali e pausa del conduttore</h2>
Il conduttore annuncia una breve pausa dal programma per motivi legati alla salute personale e ringrazia abbonati e spettatori che lo sostengono, invitando a mandare pensieri positivi durante la sua assenza.]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[[Hormozi Highlights] How to Make Your Products Better Than Your Competitors]]></title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ri3EJB_-KNA</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ri3EJB_-KNA</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>[Hormozi Highlights] <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ri3EJB_-KNA">How to Make Your Products Better Than Your Competitors</a></h1>
<h2>Relentless Care and High Standards Drive Product Quality</h2>
The creators attribute School’s success over platforms like Circle or Kajabi to a deeper level of care and a relentless pursuit of quality. Rather than optimizing for profit or rapid growth, the focus remained on making the best possible product, often at the expense of short-term gains. This internal drive set the standard for the entire organization, ensuring continuous improvement and dissatisfaction with anything less than excellence.
<h2>Attention to Detail Sets School Apart</h2>
Achieving true product greatness comes from obsessing over even the smallest details, which most competitors overlook. For example, perfecting the simple “online” green dot required deep thinking about various edge cases—like whether a user has a tab open but isn’t actively using it, or is logged in across multiple devices. This exhaustive approach to nuanced functionality results in a product that just works intuitively, making School stand out despite superficial feature similarity elsewhere.
<h2>Depth Matters More Than Surface-Level Features</h2>
Many platforms attempt to match School by copying visible features, but fail to reach the same depth of usability and design quality. The difference lies beneath the surface—School delivers features that fully address users’ needs through refined, thoughtful implementation rather than mere checkbox parity, creating an experience that feels obviously superior.
<h2>Leadership Demands the Highest Standards</h2>
The conversation emphasizes that an organization should always be led by the person with the highest standards and the ability to achieve them. As soon as someone in the company holds a higher standard than the leader, leadership should transition. This principle ensures that product quality and vision remain uncompromised.
<h2>Structured Roadmap for Scaling to $100 Million+</h2>
A proven 10-stage roadmap exists for taking companies from zero to over $100 million in revenue, with step-by-step breakdowns across key business functions and practical advice for overcoming obstacles at each stage. This roadmap has been successfully applied to a variety of business types and is offered as a free resource for viewers.]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>